<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>BrettTerpstra.com - Brett Terpstra 的疯狂科学</title>
    <link>https://brettterpstra.com/</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 18:17:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>2024 年 3 月 19 日网上游览</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16624673/web-excursions-for-march-19-2024</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Deckset, Markdown, OCR, Ground News, CleanShot X
总结:
文章介绍了一些最新的网络资源和工具。其中提到了Deckset推出iOS版本，用户可以使用Markdown在iPhone/iPad上创建演示文稿。另外推荐了一款基于Markdown的演示工具，可能比Deckset更好。还介绍了一个只适用于macOS 13+的简单命令行工具，可以使用内置的OCR和转录框架。提到了Ground News这个工具，可以帮助用户了解不同观点的新闻，打破信息茧房。最后作者推荐了CleanShot X用于截图和录屏。文章结尾提到网站受到读者支持，保留所有材料版权。 






Web excursions brought to you in partnership with CleanShot X, the absolute, hands-down best app for Mac screenshots. Get one of my all-time favorite apps here.

Deckset on the App Store
Just when I thought Deckset was dead, an iOS version is announced. Create presentations using Markdown, now on your iPhone/iPad.
iA Presenter
A newer option for Markdown-based presentations (from the creators of iA Writer and based on the same engine) that I think this might be even better than Deckset. Going to give it a test run for a while, but off the bat it looks really slick.
freedmand/textra
macOS 13+ only, a simple command line interface to the OS’s built-in OCR and transcription frameworks. The OCR works really well. Really, really well (I’m using it to add automatic ALT tags to Dimspirations and it deals with text in crazy fonts on crazy backgrounds). I haven’t gone far with testing the audio transcription, but I have high expectations.
Ground News
This is advertised on almost every YouTube channel I subscribe to, so I decided to check it out. It’s really good. If you want to break out of your news bubble and understand what the other side is hearing and thinking, Ground News provides all kinds of tools for doing so. Highly recommended. I’m trying to get my parents to use it, but even if they don’t, it helps me see the headlines that are going to affect them in their bubble so I’m not shocked when topics come up that I’ve seen no trace of previously.

I do all of my screenshots and screen recordings with CleanShot X. I love it to pieces. You should get it.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16624673/web-excursions-for-march-19-2024</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 15:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>构建自定义 URL 缩短器</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16621740/build-a-custom-url-shortener</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16621740/build-a-custom-url-shortener</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>忧郁商品！</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16598996/dimspirations-merch</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 打印和交付，Sellfy，merchandise，BrettTerpstra.com，支持者
总结:
作者在BrettTerpstra.com上推出了新的商品系列，使用Sellfy进行印刷和交付。他计划在未来扩大选择，并根据反馈调整定价。他希望读者喜欢他的作品，并提供支持。 








I’ve created the initial round of merchandise for the Dimspirations Store. I know my sense of humor isn’t for everyone, which is why this whole project is on a different site.
I’ve started with some of my personal favorites as tees, mugs, and a 2024 calendar. The collection will grow over time (it’s print-on-demand, no cost to me to expand the selection). I’ll also adjust pricing based on feedback. I think the prices are pretty competitive based on what I’ve spent on merch myself.
I’m using Sellfy for the printing and delivery. I’ve used Spring in the past and checked out Printful and Cotton Bureau, but Sellfy seemed like the best solution with the most competitive pricing. I already paid for a 1-year package, so let’s hope it works out. If it does, I’ll probably relaunch the BrettTerpstra.com (Lab) merchandise there as well.
Please do check out the store, and if you like what you see, toss a couple bucks my way. And if you don’t see what you want, be sure to upvote your favorites Dimspirations by clicking the devil below each one. If you have special requests, of course let me know.
I’ll admit, this one is my favorite:
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16598996/dimspirations-merch</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 16:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 年 2 月 29 日网上游览</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16597352/web-excursions-for-february-29-2024</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Alfred, Bunch, Colorful nihilist memes, Hyper Key, Backblaze
总结:
Alfred的workflow Cluster与Bunch紧密集成，使生活变得更加轻松。还有色彩缤纷的虚无主义迷因来提高心情。此外，还有macOS上简单而强大的键盘增强工具，Backblaze可安全可靠地将整个计算机数据备份到云端。 Matt Webb的帖子谈论了科技走入了一个令人不安的境地，但或许这并不是件坏事。 






Web excursions brought to you in partnership with Backblaze. Back up everything.

Cluster (for Bunch)
Cluster is an Alfred workflow for use with Bunch, written by Stephen Millard. Closely integrates Bunch functionality with Alfred to make life even easier. I’m not an Alfred user myself, so I haven’t stress tested it, but if you are, please do and let Stephen and I know how it goes!
Nihilisa Frank on Tumblr
Colorful nihilist memes to make your day. Thanks to @adamrice for pointing this out.
Superkey
Simple and powerful keyboard enhancement on macOS. Want to add the Hyper Key with no fuss? Want to navigate your screen without touching your trackpad/mouse? This app looks really great at $16. h/t Mike Harahan on the forum.
Tech has graduated from the Star Trek era to the Douglas Adams age (Interconnected)
This post from Matt Webb speaks to me. Yes, tech has gone into a wobbly place better envisioned by Douglas Adams than by Gene Roddenberry, but maybe that’s an ok thing.

Backblaze securely backs up your entire computer to the cloud, affordably and reliably. I trust it with all my data. Check it out today.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16597352/web-excursions-for-february-29-2024</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 21:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>如何撰写提醒电子邮件[赞助商]</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16596954/how-to-compose-reminder-emails-sponsor</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16596954/how-to-compose-reminder-emails-sponsor</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 14:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimspire.me 上的产品搜寻</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16596955/dimspire-dot-me-on-product-hunt</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ site, collection, review, support, materials
总结:文章提到了新网站的推出，作者对网站的付出和希望得到评论的愿望，以及对读者的支持。网站包含了虚无主义的灵感和壁纸。作者期待读者的支持和评论。 






On a whim I’ve put the new Dimspire.me site up on Product Hunt. I’ve been putting a lot of love into it and even if I were to stop now, I think it’s a great collection of nihilist inspirations (and wallpapers), enough to last quite a while. I’d love it if you’d take a second and leave a review.
Thanks!
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16596955/dimspire-dot-me-on-product-hunt</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 14:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>饲料中的缺陷</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16590869/dimspirations-in-your-feed</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ RSS feed, subscription, email, monetize, political

这是一篇关于Dimspire Me网站的文章，介绍了他们新增了RSS feed订阅和通过邮件订阅的功能。同时作者表示如果网站有商业化可能的话，将通过出售商品来实现，而不是收费订阅。作者还表示会尽量减少涉及政治的内容，因为有些读者对此表示反感。最后作者呼吁读者点赞和分享这篇文章以及支持他们的项目。总结：文章介绍了Dimspire Me网站新增的订阅功能以及未来可能进行商业化运营的打算，同时表示会尽量减少政治相关内容。 






I’ve added (well, fixed) the RSS feed for Dimspire.me. You can now subscribe via your favorite feed reader at Dimspirations RSS (or just enter https://dimspire.me in your subscribe field, the feeds are discoverable). The feed is available in XML and JSON flavors, and each entry just contains a pithy description and one image.
You can also sign up to receive Dimspirations in your email, max one email per day, and only when there’s new stuff:


Enter your e-mail address:




Dimspire Me


Thanks for supporting this little project. I’ve decided if I ever monetize it, it will be through merch (posters, calendars, coffee mugs, etc.). So the wallpapers and dismal inspirations will continue to be free online.
P.S. I’ve received some flack for occasionally going “political” with the Dimspirations. I don’t think things like being disgusted by a lack of gun control, being anti-genocide, or laughing at manufactured outrage are extreme political views, but I promise to keep those to a minimum. Sometimes I get a little fired up — don’t let it scare you away.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16590869/dimspirations-in-your-feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 17:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>昏暗的我</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16588973/dimspire-dot-me</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Jekyll, insomnia, website, automation, dimspirations
总结: 这篇文章讲述了作者因失眠而产生创造力，制作了一个名为Dimspirations的网站。网站基于Jekyll架构，具有自动化功能，可以生成不同尺寸的壁纸，包括iPhone版本和方形版本。作者描述了网站的页面结构和功能，包括随机生成Dimspirations的功能和下载按钮的实现方法。作者还提到了对于网站的未来计划。整篇文章表达了作者对于自己创作的热情和对网站的期望。 






I couldn’t sleep last night. I’m not manic, I’m just going through this months-long bout of insomnia. At least I don’t think I’m manic. It doesn’t have any of the characteristics of my usual mania. And up until last night I wasn’t even getting out of bed when I couldn’t sleep. But last night I did, and I made you a website.
Introducing Dimspire.me. It’s built on Jekyll and has a bunch of automations. I can essentially create a “dimspiration” using an Affinity Photo template, and then RetroBatch will output wallpaper sizes (including iPhone) and square versions for posting and populating the gallery. Just running rake will find new photos added to the assets folder and generate posts for them, which will then populate the index pages. It should be pretty simple to maintain. All documented in a Howzit notes file, of course.
The site is pretty simple: a homepage with description and the latest few posts, a “Dimspirations” page that’s essentially a blog post index but done in gallery fashion, and a random dimspiration page that will just throw single random dimspirations at you. Fun stuff.
When viewing a single Dimspiration (by clicking on any thumbnail), you get some cool UI showing edges of the previous and next Dimspiration. I like it, anyway. There’s still some work to do on certain breakpoints, but overall the styling should work on any device. And every Dimspiration page has a download button, where you can download all available versions of the current Dimspiration. This is accomplished by a Rake task that parses every post, extracts the YAML key that defines the image for the page, then zips up every file in the assets directory that matches it. It creates a manifest table that shows what’s in the zip file, with each individual file linked. So when there are wallpaper versions of a Dimspiration, you can download the set or follow a link to a specific version. Took a little thinking and tweaking, but I think it’s a good solution.
I hope you enjoy it. It’s cathartic for me to create these, and they’re getting better with time. I’m not going to try to monetize any of this at this point, but I’ve watermarked all the images so if you share them, they should trace back to me. Speaking of, I do still need to consider adding share buttons to these… but it always freaks me out how much data social sites collect when you include their button, so I’ll need to figure out ways around that. We’ll call that “next step.”
Love always,
Brett
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16588973/dimspire-dot-me</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 19:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>保留它——写笔记，保留东西，然后再次找到它们[赞助商]</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16588628/keep-it-write-notes-keep-things-and-find-them-again-sponsor</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16588628/keep-it-write-notes-keep-things-and-find-them-again-sponsor</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cerakey陶瓷键帽评测</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16580751/a-cerakey-ceramic-keycap-review</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16580751/a-cerakey-ceramic-keycap-review</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 20:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#dimspirations 回来了</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16571361/dimspirations-are-back</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ #dimspirations, automation, wallpaper, gallery, feedback
总结:作者创建了一个名为#dimspirations的系列“inspirational”海报，并自动化了壁纸格式的创建。作者考虑建立一个易于维护的网站来展示这些作品，并考虑通过Patreon等方式获取支持。读者被邀请分享反馈和建议。 






I’ve started creating Dimspirations again, my depressing-but-actually-realistic collection of “inspirational” posters. You can follow the hashtag #dimspirations on Twitter, Facebook, Mastodon, or Instagram for new posts. I’ve also automated the process of creating wallpaper-formatted version of them which get uploaded to Flickr and are also available as a zip (containing 5120x3200 and 2048x1366 versions). I should probably add an iPhone ratio to the automation, but they get harder to resize vertically from one image. Anyway, if you’re in the mood to be “dimspired,” check them out.
By the way, if you’ve never checked it out, the “Other Stuff” section (where my wallpapers are located) has some fun projects in it. Fun for me, anyway.
Side tangent: I own the domain dimspire.me, and have always meant to find a way to make an easy-to-maintain gallery out of these. Probably a blog-style thing with daily or weekly dimspirations, with basic comments functionality and links to download the square or wallpaper versions. The index page would just be a thumbnail gallery with the main image from each post. It might actually be nice to do a paywall and have the wallpaper versions supported by Patreon or something. I don’t know if anyone would actually pay for these. I’ve seen similar projects sold as books, and I feel like the designs are actually pretty good for print, so maybe someday. Anyway, my inclination is to do this site in Jekyll (which I’m very adept at), but would be open to any suggestions as to what the best way to accomplish this would be. I’m not even opposed to WordPress with some custom plugins (which I’m also surprisingly adept at), which would be pretty easy to automate and then I could use MarsEdit to maintain it. Still pondering.
In the meantime, please share your feedback (and any suggestions, should the dimspiration strike)!
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16571361/dimspirations-are-back</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 18:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 年 2 月 12 日网上游览</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16571248/web-excursions-for-february-12-2024</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Find Any File, iThoughts, photo library, GUI, BrettTerpstra.com

总结:
本文介绍了几款实用的工具和应用，其中包括Find Any File，这是一款更新不断的应用，可以帮助用户进行准确的文件搜索，并且可以搜索NAS；iThoughts则是一款思维导图工具，虽然开发者已经停止更新，但仍然是一款值得推荐的应用；此外，还有一款用于整理照片库的工具，以及一款可以直接编辑Mac应用偏好设置的GUI工具。BrettTerpstra.com也提供了支持，读者可以选择是否点赞或分享。 






Web excursions brought to you in partnership with MindMeister, the best collaborative mind mapping software out there.

Find Any File
I’ve mentioned HoudahSpot plenty of times, but there’s an app that’s been around since about 2005 that has been continually updated and only costs $6-10 that’s worth checking out if you constantly run into hard-to-find files. One major benefit of Find Any File is that it can search your NAS and doesn’t rely on Spotlight for indexing. Searches can be a little slow but they are VERY accurate. Allows saving searches and search templates, and can export found files as a list for use in scripting app… uses a pay-what-you-can shareware model (oh, the old days!). Here’s a great review from Allison Sheridan with much more detail.
toketaWare has ceased trading
If you’ve followed me for the last few years, you know I swear by iThoughts for my mind mapping needs (of which I have a lot). I’m pretty devastated to see that the developer has moved on and there will be no future releases of the app on any platform. I checked in with him, he says he’s fine, he just moved on. Fair enough. Now I have to pick a new favorite mind mapping tool. Open to your thoughts!
Photoscope - Storage Cleaner on the App Store
A tool for cleaning up your photo library by easily selecting the best image from sets of multiple/burst photos. Well done and easy to use.
Prefs Editor
From the same developer who makes Find Any File, a very handy GUI for directly editing any Mac app’s preferences. Especially great for apps that have “esoteric” or hidden preferences that require using defaults commands in Terminal. Free!

Check out MindMeister and start brainstorming, collaborating, and boosting productivity.
Like or share this post on Mastodon or Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16571248/web-excursions-for-february-12-2024</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>将 nvALT RTF 文件转换为 Markdown</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16565808/convert-nvalt-rtf-files-to-markdown</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16565808/convert-nvalt-rtf-files-to-markdown</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 17:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>检查 VPN 连接第 2 部分</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16553334/checking-for-a-vpn-connection-part-2</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ scutil, VPN连接, 脚本, grep, 网络接口

VPN连接状态检测的脚本可以通过使用scutil命令和grep来进行。通过检查返回值来确定VPN连接的状态，这个脚本可以让你更清晰地监控VPN的连接情况。总结: scutil命令和grep在脚本中被用来检测VPN连接状态，让你能够更有效地管理网络接口变化。 
Ok, so I wrote yesterday about a solution for checking your VPN connection via a network interface change, but it turns out there’s a better way to do it. I discovered it shortly after posting (StackExchange thread), and received a few comments mentioning it. So here’s part two.
The command is scutil, used for managing (s)ystem (c)onfiguration parameters. The command scutil --nc list will show your available VPN devices and their state, either Connected or Disconnected. By doing a case-sensitive grep for Connected we can determine if one or more is connected.
So now the script just look like:
#!/bin/bash

while true; do
  RES=`scutil --nc list | grep -c Connected`
  [[ $RES == 0 ]] &amp;&amp; break
  sleep 1
done

say &quot;VPN disconnected&quot;
The scutil --nc list | grep -c Connected should return 0 if no VPN is connected, which you can then use to light up a button, integrate into launch/quit scripts, etc. Just a cleaner way to do what I showed yesterday.
Trevor Manternach has an interesting post using this trick with Wirecast and Bartender.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16553334/checking-for-a-vpn-connection-part-2</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 16:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>从命令行检查 VPN 连接</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16552042/checking-for-a-vpn-connection-from-the-command-line</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16552042/checking-for-a-vpn-connection-from-the-command-line</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 19:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>