<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>BrettTerpstra.com - Brett Terpstra 的疯狂科学</title>
    <link>https://brettterpstra.com/</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 03:16:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>iThoughts 之后的生活</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16666804/life-after-ithoughts</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ MindNode, iThoughts, sunsetting, Obsidian, Curio

总结:
iThoughts宣布即将停用，作者转向使用MindNode。MindNode拥有精美界面、活跃开发、支持Mac和iOS版本，能够打开iThoughts文件，导入Markdown文件，生成任务列表等功能。此外，Obsidian插件也能提供一定的思维导图功能，但相比MindNode功能有限。值得注意的是Curio内置的思维导图也是不错的选择。 






So a lot of us are wondering what to do now that Toketaware has announced the sunsetting of the iThoughts mind mapping app for Mac and iOS. It’s very sad to see it go, but I expect the current version to continue working for a few years to come. That said, I tend to favor software that has at least somewhat of a future. So I’ve been testing the waters with some other contenders. The short story is I’m moving over to MindNode.
Why MindNode?
I’ve always appreciated MindNode (and even added support for it to Marked), but there were some things that made me prefer iThoughts over MindNode. After testing the latest version of MindNode, I can no longer remember what those things were. Probably the filtering and advanced searching in iThoughts, but for 90% of my mind map purposes, it looks like MindNode will do just fine. I think the last time I made the comparison, MindNode was lacking some of the features it has these days.
I’m not going into nearly the depth that Allison Sheridan did over on Podfeet with her mind map comparison, but I’ll list some of the pros of MindNode for my purposes:

Looks great
Actively developed
Mac and iOS versions
Opens iThoughts (.itmz) files, so I don’t have to fret about losing old mind maps
Imports Markdown files
Can create tasks from nodes (can’t do much with them other than check them off, but it’s handy for packing lists)
Exports Markdown and OPML, among other formats
Works with Marked (File-&gt;Advanced-&gt;Preview in Marked)
Good keyboard navigation with some customization options
Quick entry from tool bar
It’s on Setapp

Other options
If you’re an Obsidian user, there are some mind mapping plugins available. The “Enhancing Mind Maps” plugin is a decent option if you’re in Obsidian all the time anyway:
Pros:

Built into obsidian
Basic keyboard navigation
Transparent layer over plain Markdown files, easily portable and future-proof
Works great with Marked using the obsidian-md-filter processor (via Conductor!), and you can easily connect the two with my plugin (which is still waiting for acceptance into the Community Plugins…)

Cons:

Lacks a ton of features compared to MindNode

I would also point out that the mind mapping built into Curio is pretty good, and has the benefit of fitting into the crazy cool integrations that Curio provides, linking to other notes and objects, and fitting into an overall project management system.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16666804/life-after-ithoughts</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 22:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>标记导体简介</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16664804/introducing-the-marked-conductor</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16664804/introducing-the-marked-conductor</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 18:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 年 4 月 22 日网上游览</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16657056/web-excursions-for-april-22-2024</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Google Cemetery, figlet/toilet ascii art, BetterTouchTool MacOS automation, Marked plugin for Obsidian, NordVPN
总结:Google Cemetery提供了Google终止的产品列表，其中可能有一些你从未听说过的产品。xero提供了大量figlet/toilet ascii艺术字体。BetterTouchTool是一个可以用JavaScript进行MacOS自动化的工具。作者制作了一个适用于Obsidian的Marked插件。NordVPN不仅可以保护你的网络浏览安全，还可以让你的IP地址看起来来自任何国家。 






Web excursions brought to you in partnership with NordVPN. Secure your internet browsing effectively and affordably.

Google Graveyard - Killed by Google


Killed by Google is the Google Graveyard. A full list of dead products killed by Google in the Google Cemetery. Up-to-date and shocking in scope. I bet there are a few on here you’d never even realized were a thing.


xero/figlet-fonts
A huge collection of figlet/toilet ascii art fonts from xero.
btt.js
BetterTouchTool MacOS automation in JS. I haven’t played with this yet but it looks really fun. Let me know if you take it for a spin.
ttscoff/Marked2-obsidian
I made a Marked plugin for Obsidian. It’s my first try and I really don’t know what I’m doing, but it seems to work perfectly. Waiting for it to be included in the Community Plugins for easy install (which could have happened by the time this goes live), but you can install from the source if you’re anxious.

NordVPN secures your internet browsing, plus it can make it look to services like you’re coming from any country. Check it out today.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16657056/web-excursions-for-april-22-2024</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>对 nvALT 用户的呼吁</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16655625/a-plea-to-nvalt-users</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ nvALT, end of life, modernize, Markdown files, nvUltra

nvALT已经停止更新，目前几乎无法在现代操作系统上正常运行。建议用户将存储方式转为Markdown文件，以便顺利迁移到新的笔记系统。如果笔记存储为富文本文件(RTF)，则需使用其他应用如nvUltra、The Archive或Obsidian。学习Markdown并不难，只需了解一些简单的语法规则。立即将存储方式改为纯文本文件，以免在nvALT无法运行时无法提取笔记。可能会为nvUltra编写导入器，但目前尚未实现。要获取nvUltra测试版，请通过网站联系链接发送邮件。 
I’ve said this before, but I need to keep repeating it based on the number of queries I get. nvALT is at end of life, unless someone picks up the reigns and modernizes the (open source) code base. As it stands now, nvALT barely functions on modern OSs.
Fletcher Penney and I have designed nvALT’s successor, nvUltra, to work only with a folder full of Markdown files, which is the only way I recommend using nvALT. If your nvALT files are stored as individual Markdown files, switching to nvUltra is no problem, nor is switching to any other Notational-Velocity-like system. It will even work in Obsidian. But if you store your notes as a database only, you’re screwed when nvALT stops working for you.
So please, if nvALT is still running for you, go into Preferences-&gt;Notes-&gt;Storage and change “Store and read notes on disk as” to “Plain Text Files.” If your previous storage method was database, all of your notes will be immediately written out as plain text files, safe and secure and easy to port to a new (working) notes system. The files will now be in the same folder nvALT shows in the folder selector at the top of the Notes preference pane.







nvALT is not even working well enough for me to get a full screenshot. But here is my best attempt.

If your notes are stored as Rich Text Files (RTF), you’ll need to convert them to Markdown to make use of other apps like nvUltra, The Archive, or Obsidian. If you don’t know Markdown, don’t sweat it. It’s very easy to learn and it’s really just plain text, so as long as you know how to write, you’re already kind of writing Markdown. It’s only necessary to learn any syntax if you need to do things like create bulleted/numbered lists, add bold or italics, or create links.
So, again, please immediately switch your storage method to plain text files. The nvALT database format has no easy out for people ready to switch. I may try to write an importer for nvUltra (or generally to output Markdown), but I have not done so yet.
If you want on the nvUltra beta, email me through the contact link on nvultra.com.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16655625/a-plea-to-nvalt-users</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 14:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>回到我的时代……关于当时和现在写博客的一些想法</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16642792/back-in-my-day-dot-dot-dot-some-thoughts-on-blogging-then-and-now</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16642792/back-in-my-day-dot-dot-dot-some-thoughts-on-blogging-then-and-now</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 20:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CurlyQ 和自动化 JavaScript 执行</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16641718/curlyq-and-automated-javascript-execution</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ gem install curlyq, JavaScript execution, screenshot command, execute subcommand, web automation tool 

总结: 作者在文章中介绍了对CurlyQ工具的改进，包括添加JavaScript执行功能、改进截图命令、新增执行子命令等。通过对工具的升级，用户可以更方便地进行网页自动化操作，如保存网页截图、执行特定脚本等。这些改进将极大地提高用户的工作效率，特别适用于自动化文档生成等工作。CurlyQ的最新版本已可通过gem install curlyq进行更新或安装。 
I’ve been wanting to add JavaScript execution to CurlyQ for a while and finally got around to it.
In case you’ve missed it, CurlyQ is my command-line web automation tool for fetching, parsing, and responding to web page content, designed to be used as part of a *NIX pipeline. It can grab titles, links, metadata, and more from any web page. As part of its functionality, it can also use Firefox or Chrome to save screenshots, and that’s part of what I’ve improved.
The screenshot command now accepts a --script parameter. This can be a JavaScript string, or - to read from STDIN, or a path to a file which will be read and executed before taking a screenshot. You can also now define an element ID to wait for before taking the screenshot (or executing the script) using --id ELEMENT_ID. As long as the ID is a valid element on the page, the screenshot will trigger once that element is loaded (via HTML or dynamically), with a timeout of 10 seconds. You can also define a --wait X flag in the command to wait for a specified number of seconds after executing a script before the screenshot is taken.
Further, I’ve added a new subcommand, execute, that has the same parameters as above and simply allows you to load a page in the browser and execute a script on it. I really wanted this because it’s the easiest way to automate NiftyMenu:
curlyq execute -b chrome -s &quot;NiftyAPI.find(&#39;file/save&#39;).arrow().shoot(&#39;file-save&#39;)&quot; file:///Users/ttscoff/Desktop/Code/niftymenu/dist/MultiMarkdown-Composer.html
That command will save a screenshot of the File-&gt;Save menu item for me, allowing me to fully automate menu screenshots for any of my apps. I can have NiftyMenu generate an up-to-date view of the app’s menu bar, with styling for the current OS, and output detailed screenshots with callouts automatically. This will be a huge timesaver when it comes to documentation.
You can update/install the latest version of CurlyQ with gem install curlyq. The improvements in this post are available as of version 0.0.12. Enjoy!
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16641718/curlyq-and-automated-javascript-execution</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 18:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>关于使用 CDN</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16638813/on-using-a-cdn</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16638813/on-using-a-cdn</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 21:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>自动化 Dimspirations 工作流程</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16637190/automating-the-dimspirations-workflow</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16637190/automating-the-dimspirations-workflow</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 19:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 年 3 月 29 日网上游览</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16635234/web-excursions-for-march-29-2024</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ mac app; intention setting; Terminal trick; native macOS email client; keycap replacement
总结: 这篇文章介绍了一款简单优雅的Mac应用程序，可以帮助用户设定意图并提醒他们专注工作。还分享了一个适用于Terminal爱好者的技巧，并推荐了一款优秀的原生macOS邮件客户端。最后提到了订购了一个键帽来替换现有的定制键帽。 






Web excursions brought to you in partnership with CleanMyMac X, all the tools to speed up your Mac, in one app.

N₁₀ - Attention Management App for Mac
A simple, elegant Mac app that allows you to set an intention, define how much time you plan to put into it, and then just sit, quietly reminding you of what you want to be working on with subtle but all-encompassing animations. Perfect for those of us who say “OK, now I’m really going to work on this” and then find ourselves doing something entirely different within five minutes H/T Jason Rhemus and props to props to developer Sam Stephenson.
Again with man pages and BBEdit - All this
Really nice trick for Terminal junkies who use BBEdit. I have a similar trick for sublime, and one that opens man pages in Preview, but this one provides additional navigation that none of mine have.
Mimestream
“A native macOS email client for Gmail.” This looks so good, especially considering MailPlane is dead. If only I didn’t have iCloud and Exchange email accounts I need to deal with, too.
Interstellar Resin Keycap
I ordered this keycap to replace my custom rocket keycap that I use for my hyper key. Available in 2.25u (Enter) size. It should arrive today and I’m very excited. I’ll post pictures once I’ve installed it!


Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16635234/web-excursions-for-march-29-2024</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 17:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>重新审视 TagFiler 和 Vitag</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16628513/revisiting-tagfiler-and-vitag</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16628513/revisiting-tagfiler-and-vitag</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 年 3 月 19 日网上游览</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16624673/web-excursions-for-march-19-2024</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Deckset, Markdown, OCR, Ground News, CleanShot X
总结:
文章介绍了一些最新的网络资源和工具。其中提到了Deckset推出iOS版本，用户可以使用Markdown在iPhone/iPad上创建演示文稿。另外推荐了一款基于Markdown的演示工具，可能比Deckset更好。还介绍了一个只适用于macOS 13+的简单命令行工具，可以使用内置的OCR和转录框架。提到了Ground News这个工具，可以帮助用户了解不同观点的新闻，打破信息茧房。最后作者推荐了CleanShot X用于截图和录屏。文章结尾提到网站受到读者支持，保留所有材料版权。 






Web excursions brought to you in partnership with CleanShot X, the absolute, hands-down best app for Mac screenshots. Get one of my all-time favorite apps here.

Deckset on the App Store
Just when I thought Deckset was dead, an iOS version is announced. Create presentations using Markdown, now on your iPhone/iPad.
iA Presenter
A newer option for Markdown-based presentations (from the creators of iA Writer and based on the same engine) that I think this might be even better than Deckset. Going to give it a test run for a while, but off the bat it looks really slick.
freedmand/textra
macOS 13+ only, a simple command line interface to the OS’s built-in OCR and transcription frameworks. The OCR works really well. Really, really well (I’m using it to add automatic ALT tags to Dimspirations and it deals with text in crazy fonts on crazy backgrounds). I haven’t gone far with testing the audio transcription, but I have high expectations.
Ground News
This is advertised on almost every YouTube channel I subscribe to, so I decided to check it out. It’s really good. If you want to break out of your news bubble and understand what the other side is hearing and thinking, Ground News provides all kinds of tools for doing so. Highly recommended. I’m trying to get my parents to use it, but even if they don’t, it helps me see the headlines that are going to affect them in their bubble so I’m not shocked when topics come up that I’ve seen no trace of previously.

I do all of my screenshots and screen recordings with CleanShot X. I love it to pieces. You should get it.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16624673/web-excursions-for-march-19-2024</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 15:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>构建自定义 URL 缩短器</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16621740/build-a-custom-url-shortener</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16621740/build-a-custom-url-shortener</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimspirations 商品！</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16598996/dimspirations-merch</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 打印和交付，Sellfy，merchandise，BrettTerpstra.com，支持者
总结:
作者在BrettTerpstra.com上推出了新的商品系列，使用Sellfy进行印刷和交付。他计划在未来扩大选择，并根据反馈调整定价。他希望读者喜欢他的作品，并提供支持。 








I’ve created the initial round of merchandise for the Dimspirations Store. I know my sense of humor isn’t for everyone, which is why this whole project is on a different site.
I’ve started with some of my personal favorites as tees, mugs, and a 2024 calendar. The collection will grow over time (it’s print-on-demand, no cost to me to expand the selection). I’ll also adjust pricing based on feedback. I think the prices are pretty competitive based on what I’ve spent on merch myself.
I’m using Sellfy for the printing and delivery. I’ve used Spring in the past and checked out Printful and Cotton Bureau, but Sellfy seemed like the best solution with the most competitive pricing. I already paid for a 1-year package, so let’s hope it works out. If it does, I’ll probably relaunch the BrettTerpstra.com (Lab) merchandise there as well.
Please do check out the store, and if you like what you see, toss a couple bucks my way. And if you don’t see what you want, be sure to upvote your favorites Dimspirations by clicking the devil below each one. If you have special requests, of course let me know.
I’ll admit, this one is my favorite:
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16598996/dimspirations-merch</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 16:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 年 2 月 29 日网上游览</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16597352/web-excursions-for-february-29-2024</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Alfred, Bunch, Colorful nihilist memes, Hyper Key, Backblaze
总结:
Alfred的workflow Cluster与Bunch紧密集成，使生活变得更加轻松。还有色彩缤纷的虚无主义迷因来提高心情。此外，还有macOS上简单而强大的键盘增强工具，Backblaze可安全可靠地将整个计算机数据备份到云端。 Matt Webb的帖子谈论了科技走入了一个令人不安的境地，但或许这并不是件坏事。 






Web excursions brought to you in partnership with Backblaze. Back up everything.

Cluster (for Bunch)
Cluster is an Alfred workflow for use with Bunch, written by Stephen Millard. Closely integrates Bunch functionality with Alfred to make life even easier. I’m not an Alfred user myself, so I haven’t stress tested it, but if you are, please do and let Stephen and I know how it goes!
Nihilisa Frank on Tumblr
Colorful nihilist memes to make your day. Thanks to @adamrice for pointing this out.
Superkey
Simple and powerful keyboard enhancement on macOS. Want to add the Hyper Key with no fuss? Want to navigate your screen without touching your trackpad/mouse? This app looks really great at $16. h/t Mike Harahan on the forum.
Tech has graduated from the Star Trek era to the Douglas Adams age (Interconnected)
This post from Matt Webb speaks to me. Yes, tech has gone into a wobbly place better envisioned by Douglas Adams than by Gene Roddenberry, but maybe that’s an ok thing.

Backblaze securely backs up your entire computer to the cloud, affordably and reliably. I trust it with all my data. Check it out today.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16597352/web-excursions-for-february-29-2024</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 21:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>如何撰写提醒电子邮件[赞助商]</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16596954/how-to-compose-reminder-emails-sponsor</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16596954/how-to-compose-reminder-emails-sponsor</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 14:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>