<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>BrettTerpstra.com - Brett Terpstra 的疯狂科学</title>
    <link>https://brettterpstra.com/</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 18:18:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>如何撰写提醒电子邮件[赞助商]</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16596954/how-to-compose-reminder-emails-sponsor</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16596954/how-to-compose-reminder-emails-sponsor</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 14:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimspire.me 上的产品搜寻</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16596955/dimspire-dot-me-on-product-hunt</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ site, collection, review, support, materials
总结:文章提到了新网站的推出，作者对网站的付出和希望得到评论的愿望，以及对读者的支持。网站包含了虚无主义的灵感和壁纸。作者期待读者的支持和评论。 






On a whim I’ve put the new Dimspire.me site up on Product Hunt. I’ve been putting a lot of love into it and even if I were to stop now, I think it’s a great collection of nihilist inspirations (and wallpapers), enough to last quite a while. I’d love it if you’d take a second and leave a review.
Thanks!
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16596955/dimspire-dot-me-on-product-hunt</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 14:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>饲料中的缺陷</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16590869/dimspirations-in-your-feed</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ RSS feed, subscription, email, monetize, political

这是一篇关于Dimspire Me网站的文章，介绍了他们新增了RSS feed订阅和通过邮件订阅的功能。同时作者表示如果网站有商业化可能的话，将通过出售商品来实现，而不是收费订阅。作者还表示会尽量减少涉及政治的内容，因为有些读者对此表示反感。最后作者呼吁读者点赞和分享这篇文章以及支持他们的项目。总结：文章介绍了Dimspire Me网站新增的订阅功能以及未来可能进行商业化运营的打算，同时表示会尽量减少政治相关内容。 






I’ve added (well, fixed) the RSS feed for Dimspire.me. You can now subscribe via your favorite feed reader at Dimspirations RSS (or just enter https://dimspire.me in your subscribe field, the feeds are discoverable). The feed is available in XML and JSON flavors, and each entry just contains a pithy description and one image.
You can also sign up to receive Dimspirations in your email, max one email per day, and only when there’s new stuff:


Enter your e-mail address:




Dimspire Me


Thanks for supporting this little project. I’ve decided if I ever monetize it, it will be through merch (posters, calendars, coffee mugs, etc.). So the wallpapers and dismal inspirations will continue to be free online.
P.S. I’ve received some flack for occasionally going “political” with the Dimspirations. I don’t think things like being disgusted by a lack of gun control, being anti-genocide, or laughing at manufactured outrage are extreme political views, but I promise to keep those to a minimum. Sometimes I get a little fired up — don’t let it scare you away.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16590869/dimspirations-in-your-feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 17:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>昏暗的我</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16588973/dimspire-dot-me</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Jekyll, insomnia, website, automation, dimspirations
总结: 这篇文章讲述了作者因失眠而产生创造力，制作了一个名为Dimspirations的网站。网站基于Jekyll架构，具有自动化功能，可以生成不同尺寸的壁纸，包括iPhone版本和方形版本。作者描述了网站的页面结构和功能，包括随机生成Dimspirations的功能和下载按钮的实现方法。作者还提到了对于网站的未来计划。整篇文章表达了作者对于自己创作的热情和对网站的期望。 






I couldn’t sleep last night. I’m not manic, I’m just going through this months-long bout of insomnia. At least I don’t think I’m manic. It doesn’t have any of the characteristics of my usual mania. And up until last night I wasn’t even getting out of bed when I couldn’t sleep. But last night I did, and I made you a website.
Introducing Dimspire.me. It’s built on Jekyll and has a bunch of automations. I can essentially create a “dimspiration” using an Affinity Photo template, and then RetroBatch will output wallpaper sizes (including iPhone) and square versions for posting and populating the gallery. Just running rake will find new photos added to the assets folder and generate posts for them, which will then populate the index pages. It should be pretty simple to maintain. All documented in a Howzit notes file, of course.
The site is pretty simple: a homepage with description and the latest few posts, a “Dimspirations” page that’s essentially a blog post index but done in gallery fashion, and a random dimspiration page that will just throw single random dimspirations at you. Fun stuff.
When viewing a single Dimspiration (by clicking on any thumbnail), you get some cool UI showing edges of the previous and next Dimspiration. I like it, anyway. There’s still some work to do on certain breakpoints, but overall the styling should work on any device. And every Dimspiration page has a download button, where you can download all available versions of the current Dimspiration. This is accomplished by a Rake task that parses every post, extracts the YAML key that defines the image for the page, then zips up every file in the assets directory that matches it. It creates a manifest table that shows what’s in the zip file, with each individual file linked. So when there are wallpaper versions of a Dimspiration, you can download the set or follow a link to a specific version. Took a little thinking and tweaking, but I think it’s a good solution.
I hope you enjoy it. It’s cathartic for me to create these, and they’re getting better with time. I’m not going to try to monetize any of this at this point, but I’ve watermarked all the images so if you share them, they should trace back to me. Speaking of, I do still need to consider adding share buttons to these… but it always freaks me out how much data social sites collect when you include their button, so I’ll need to figure out ways around that. We’ll call that “next step.”
Love always,
Brett
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16588973/dimspire-dot-me</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 19:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>保留它——写笔记，保留东西，然后再次找到它们[赞助商]</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16588628/keep-it-write-notes-keep-things-and-find-them-again-sponsor</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16588628/keep-it-write-notes-keep-things-and-find-them-again-sponsor</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cerakey陶瓷键帽评测</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16580751/a-cerakey-ceramic-keycap-review</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16580751/a-cerakey-ceramic-keycap-review</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 20:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#dimspirations 回来了</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16571361/dimspirations-are-back</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ #dimspirations, automation, wallpaper, gallery, feedback
总结:作者创建了一个名为#dimspirations的系列“inspirational”海报，并自动化了壁纸格式的创建。作者考虑建立一个易于维护的网站来展示这些作品，并考虑通过Patreon等方式获取支持。读者被邀请分享反馈和建议。 






I’ve started creating Dimspirations again, my depressing-but-actually-realistic collection of “inspirational” posters. You can follow the hashtag #dimspirations on Twitter, Facebook, Mastodon, or Instagram for new posts. I’ve also automated the process of creating wallpaper-formatted version of them which get uploaded to Flickr and are also available as a zip (containing 5120x3200 and 2048x1366 versions). I should probably add an iPhone ratio to the automation, but they get harder to resize vertically from one image. Anyway, if you’re in the mood to be “dimspired,” check them out.
By the way, if you’ve never checked it out, the “Other Stuff” section (where my wallpapers are located) has some fun projects in it. Fun for me, anyway.
Side tangent: I own the domain dimspire.me, and have always meant to find a way to make an easy-to-maintain gallery out of these. Probably a blog-style thing with daily or weekly dimspirations, with basic comments functionality and links to download the square or wallpaper versions. The index page would just be a thumbnail gallery with the main image from each post. It might actually be nice to do a paywall and have the wallpaper versions supported by Patreon or something. I don’t know if anyone would actually pay for these. I’ve seen similar projects sold as books, and I feel like the designs are actually pretty good for print, so maybe someday. Anyway, my inclination is to do this site in Jekyll (which I’m very adept at), but would be open to any suggestions as to what the best way to accomplish this would be. I’m not even opposed to WordPress with some custom plugins (which I’m also surprisingly adept at), which would be pretty easy to automate and then I could use MarsEdit to maintain it. Still pondering.
In the meantime, please share your feedback (and any suggestions, should the dimspiration strike)!
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16571361/dimspirations-are-back</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 18:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 年 2 月 12 日网上游览</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16571248/web-excursions-for-february-12-2024</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Find Any File, iThoughts, photo library, GUI, BrettTerpstra.com

总结:
本文介绍了几款实用的工具和应用，其中包括Find Any File，这是一款更新不断的应用，可以帮助用户进行准确的文件搜索，并且可以搜索NAS；iThoughts则是一款思维导图工具，虽然开发者已经停止更新，但仍然是一款值得推荐的应用；此外，还有一款用于整理照片库的工具，以及一款可以直接编辑Mac应用偏好设置的GUI工具。BrettTerpstra.com也提供了支持，读者可以选择是否点赞或分享。 






Web excursions brought to you in partnership with MindMeister, the best collaborative mind mapping software out there.

Find Any File
I’ve mentioned HoudahSpot plenty of times, but there’s an app that’s been around since about 2005 that has been continually updated and only costs $6-10 that’s worth checking out if you constantly run into hard-to-find files. One major benefit of Find Any File is that it can search your NAS and doesn’t rely on Spotlight for indexing. Searches can be a little slow but they are VERY accurate. Allows saving searches and search templates, and can export found files as a list for use in scripting app… uses a pay-what-you-can shareware model (oh, the old days!). Here’s a great review from Allison Sheridan with much more detail.
toketaWare has ceased trading
If you’ve followed me for the last few years, you know I swear by iThoughts for my mind mapping needs (of which I have a lot). I’m pretty devastated to see that the developer has moved on and there will be no future releases of the app on any platform. I checked in with him, he says he’s fine, he just moved on. Fair enough. Now I have to pick a new favorite mind mapping tool. Open to your thoughts!
Photoscope - Storage Cleaner on the App Store
A tool for cleaning up your photo library by easily selecting the best image from sets of multiple/burst photos. Well done and easy to use.
Prefs Editor
From the same developer who makes Find Any File, a very handy GUI for directly editing any Mac app’s preferences. Especially great for apps that have “esoteric” or hidden preferences that require using defaults commands in Terminal. Free!

Check out MindMeister and start brainstorming, collaborating, and boosting productivity.
Like or share this post on Mastodon or Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16571248/web-excursions-for-february-12-2024</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>将 nvALT RTF 文件转换为 Markdown</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16565808/convert-nvalt-rtf-files-to-markdown</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16565808/convert-nvalt-rtf-files-to-markdown</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 17:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>检查 VPN 连接第 2 部分</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16553334/checking-for-a-vpn-connection-part-2</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ scutil, VPN连接, 脚本, grep, 网络接口

VPN连接状态检测的脚本可以通过使用scutil命令和grep来进行。通过检查返回值来确定VPN连接的状态，这个脚本可以让你更清晰地监控VPN的连接情况。总结: scutil命令和grep在脚本中被用来检测VPN连接状态，让你能够更有效地管理网络接口变化。 
Ok, so I wrote yesterday about a solution for checking your VPN connection via a network interface change, but it turns out there’s a better way to do it. I discovered it shortly after posting (StackExchange thread), and received a few comments mentioning it. So here’s part two.
The command is scutil, used for managing (s)ystem (c)onfiguration parameters. The command scutil --nc list will show your available VPN devices and their state, either Connected or Disconnected. By doing a case-sensitive grep for Connected we can determine if one or more is connected.
So now the script just look like:
#!/bin/bash

while true; do
  RES=`scutil --nc list | grep -c Connected`
  [[ $RES == 0 ]] &amp;&amp; break
  sleep 1
done

say &quot;VPN disconnected&quot;
The scutil --nc list | grep -c Connected should return 0 if no VPN is connected, which you can then use to light up a button, integrate into launch/quit scripts, etc. Just a cleaner way to do what I showed yesterday.
Trevor Manternach has an interesting post using this trick with Wirecast and Bartender.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16553334/checking-for-a-vpn-connection-part-2</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 16:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>从命令行检查 VPN 连接</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16552042/checking-for-a-vpn-connection-from-the-command-line</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16552042/checking-for-a-vpn-connection-from-the-command-line</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 19:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ScreenFloat 2 -- 增强你的屏幕截图 [赞助商]</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16547664/screenfloat-2-power-up-your-screenshots-sponsor</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ ScreenFloat, features, capture, annotations, organization
总结:ScreenFloat是一个强大的屏幕截图工具，具有多种新功能和工具，包括截图、标注、组织等。它可以让用户轻松地进行屏幕截图、录制屏幕、添加标注和整理截图，非常方便实用。ScreensFloat的新版本提供了诸多升级，能够让用户更加高效地进行屏幕截图和管理。 
Thanks to ScreenFloat for sponsoring BrettTerpstra.com this week! I was a frequent user of the original version, and I’m very excited to see version 2 released. It’s chock full of new features and tools that set it apart from the competition.








Hi, my name’s Matthias, I’m the developer of Yoink, Transloader, and Tameno, among others.
Allow me to introduce another one of my apps to you: ScreenFloat. Over eleven years after its initial v1 release, and after more than a year and a half of development, ScreenFloat 2 is finally here — rebuilt from the ground up, based on the core functionality that made it so beloved, but improving it in numerous, incredibly useful ways.
Capture screenshots, record your screen, or take timed screenshots. Re-capture shots without painstakingly reframing them. Import from your clipboard, other apps, your Desktop, or your iOS devices.
Float screenshots and recordings above all your other windows, apps and spaces, so information or reference material is always visible, no matter what you do. It’s like picture-in-picture, but for your captures.
Texts, faces and barcodes are detected in every shot you take and can effortlessly be extracted/copied and non-destructively redacted with a simple right-click.
Mark up and annotate your screenshots with lines, arrows, checkmarks, highlights, smart bullet points, redactions and more. All non-destructively, so you can always go back and make changes or restore the original capture.
Pick colors from any floating shot. Crop, “fold”, resize, rotate, “de-retinize”, trim, and mute your shots.
Sharing floating shots is just a file drag away, with on-the-fly changing of file format and sizing options, whether or not annotations should be included, and more.
Set up double-click workflows for repetitive tasks, like de-retinize the shot, resize it to 75% and then attach it to an email.
Your captures are stored in ScreenFloat’s Shots Browser, where you can name, tag, favorite and rate them, and organize them with folders and smart folders. They can also (optionally) be synchronized across your Macs over iCloud.
Find all your shots system-wide or in the Shots Browser by their metadata — including detected text and barcode content.
And more!
A screenshot is just a screenshot. Until you use ScreenFloat. Check it out today.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16547664/screenfloat-2-power-up-your-screenshots-sponsor</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 年 1 月 18 日网上游览</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16539501/web-excursions-for-january-18-2024</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ ScreenFloat, CleanShot X, macOS, Backblaze, keybindings
总结:本文介绍了Matthias Gansrigler发布的ScreenFloat v2，以及macOS中隐藏的代理图标的显示技巧。另外还推荐了一款可以调查macOS文本系统按键绑定的应用程序。同时还提到了一个有关双相情感障碍生活的纪录片。文章最后介绍了Backblaze，这是一款用于将计算机数据安全备份到云端的工具。
 






Web excursions brought to you in partnership with Backblaze. Back up everything.

Eternal Storms Software - ScreenFloat
Matthias Gansrigler has released v2 of ScreenFloat, one of my favorite apps from years ago. A lot of its functionality was replaced by CleanShot X for me in recent years, but the shots browser, tagging, and smart folders set it apart. The basic idea is you can float a screenshot above all other windows and it follows you between spaces, but v2 goes a lot further. Check it out.
TipBITS: Always Show Window Proxy Icons
Back in 2020 I published a tip to make the now-hidden proxy icons in macOS show up instantly on rollover, but it turns out that since then Apple has added a preference to just show them all the time. Thanks to Pim for pointing this out.
davidbalbert/KeyBinding-Inspector
An app to survey your macOS text system keybindings. I’ve been writing a lot about editing the DefaultKeyBinding.dict file, and this app makes it easy to peruse what key combinations are doing what. The biggest shortfall is that it doesn’t handle nested bindings (multi-keystroke), but it does successfully ignore those and show you everything else.
Commit Art
Turn your contributions into a tangible piece of art! Mine for 2023 is a documentation of my bipolar type 2 life.

Backblaze securely backs up your entire computer to the cloud, affordably and reliably. I trust it with all my data. Check it out today.
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16539501/web-excursions-for-january-18-2024</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 19:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CurlyQ 的屏幕截图</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16537593/screenshots-with-curlyq</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16537593/screenshots-with-curlyq</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>调酒师赠品！</title>
      <link>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16534736/bartender-giveaway</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Bartender, giveaway, macOS, menu bar, workflow
总结: 这篇文章介绍了一次Bartender软件的赠送活动，该软件可以管理Mac的菜单栏，让用户将不经常使用的菜单项移动到次要菜单中，通过快捷键和触发器控制菜单栏项目，提高工作效率。活动将于1月19日抽出10名获奖者，每人获得价值16美元的Bartender软件一份。参与者需要提供名和姓才能参加抽奖。此外，文章还介绍了网站，提到了BrettTerpstra.com受到读者支持，作者也征集下一个赠送活动的建议。 






I’m excited to offer the next giveaway, 10 licenses ($16 value each) for Bartender. Bartender tames your Mac menu bar. You can move all the stuff you don’t always need to see into a secondary menu bar, navigate the menu bar(s) with shortcuts, and even control menu bar items like Time Machine, Battery, and Wi-fi.
From the developer:

Bartender is an award-winning app for macOS that superpowers your menu bar, giving you total control over your menu bar items, what’s displayed, and when, with menu bar items only showing when you need them. Bartender improves your workflow with quick reveal, search, custom hotkeys and triggers, and lots more.







Check out the Bartender site for more info.
Sign up below to enter. Winners will be randomly drawn on Friday, January 19, at 12pm Central. The drawing is for 10 licenses ($16 value each) for Bartender, one per winner. Note that if you’re reading this via RSS, you’ll need to visit this post on brettterpstra.com to enter!
New rule: All signups must have a first and last name in order to be eligible. Entries with only a first name will be skipped by the giveaway robot. A lot of the vendors in this series require first and last names for generating license codes, and your cooperation is appreciated!

Giveaway ends in...

You need to view this post on brettterpstra.com to enter.
Stay tuned for more giveaways every week through September, 2024 (and maybe beyond).
If you have an app you’d love to see featured in this series of giveaways, let me know. Also be sure to sign up for the mailing list or follow me on Mastodon so you can be (among) the first to know about these!
Like or share this post Twitter.

BrettTerpstra.com is supported by readers like you. Click here if you&#39;d like to help out.
All materials ©2024 Brett Terpstra
Twitter | Mastodon | GitHub | Privacy Policy]]></description>
      <guid>https://brett.trpstra.net/link/535/16534736/bartender-giveaway</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>