<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Byte Tank - Pedro Lopes 博客</title>
    <link>https://lopespm.com/</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 18:23:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>与现实的联系</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/09/15/connection_with_reality.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 。 




随着我们经历大量人工智能生成内容的增加，本文将介绍与现实和自然的联系不仅为您的业务和手艺，而且为您自己带来的作用和附加价值。
取得平衡
几年来，散步或徒步旅行一直是我每周的习惯，也是我最喜欢的活动之一。
我发现在办公室/家外散步并与周围世界保持联系至关重要，无论是在大自然中还是在城市周围。这对于像我这样每天在电脑前工作的人来说尤其重要。
我喜欢沉浸在数字世界中，思考抽象的概念，并使用数字设备，例如将这些内容传达给你。但和其他任何事情一样，需要保持平衡，数字领域和现实领域之间的平衡似乎至关重要。

与现实联系的附加价值
随着生成模型的改进，越来越多的人会认为给定的文本、图像或视频可能是假的，我相信通过亲身体验、旅行、精神或认证实体的数字内容消费等体验与现实世界建立联系的需求会增加。
能够证明自己与现实世界和真实人物有联系的企业和创作者可能会在噪音中脱颖而出。
因此，如果您正在创建一家企业、一段内容或任何东西，请思考它与现实世界有何关联。问问自己：您如何提供这种联系？您如何提供现实即服务？
让自己与现实保持联系
除此之外，同样重要的是，您要保持与现实的联系。
因此，如果您觉得自己在互联网、数字设备、电视剧等方面花费了太多时间，我邀请您到户外，到外面的世界去。它是免费的，可以访问。您只需要打开门走出去，前提是您足够幸运，拥有所需的身体能力。我确信它会让你的生活变得更好。]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/09/15/connection_with_reality.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>前中央情报局情报官员的采访记录</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/09/12/interview_learnings_cia.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/09/12/interview_learnings_cia.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obsidian 加密备份 - Google Drive、Dropbox、OneDrive</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/09/11/obsidian-backup.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/09/11/obsidian-backup.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>投资追踪 - 免费电子表格模板</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/09/01/investment-tracker.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/09/01/investment-tracker.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>英国投资指南</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/08/26/uk-investment-guide.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/08/26/uk-investment-guide.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>个人本地（Llama3 8B）法学硕士 (LLM) 扩展至 WhatsApp + Obsidian 数据</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/machine_learning/2024/06/24/personal-llm.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/machine_learning/2024/06/24/personal-llm.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>超然</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/06/09/aloof.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Einstein, ramble, safety, environment, agency
总结:文章讲述了爱因斯坦的故事和作者自己的体会。爱因斯坦常常徜徉在自己的思绪中，而作者则喜欢在漫步中思考问题、策略和得出结论。他认为这种思维过程的基础是安全感。环境对一个人的影响很大，不安全的环境会限制思考和行动，而拥有选择的权利则能让人有更多自主权决定生活的方向。因此，我们应该尽量控制可以控制的部分，做出对长远有利的选择。 
Einstein’s rambles
I’ve been listening to the “Einstein: His Life and Universe” audiobook, from Walter Isaacson, which recounts a series of curious stories of how he carried himself through his life.
Einstein was often known to be aloof and lost in this thoughts, so much so that when sailing his clunky 15-foot sailboat named Tinef (Yiddish for “worthless” or “junk”), he often found himself to being rescued more than once by locals near to his rented a summer cottage overlooking Cutchogue Harbor.
Another delightful story was when he lived in Princeton, where occasionally, he would take rambling walks on his own. One day, called into the Institute for Advanced Study, where he worked, and asked to speak to a particular dean. When the secretary said that the dean wasn’t available, he hesitantly asked for Einstein’s home address. That was not possible to give out, he was informed. His voice then dropped to a whisper. “Please don’t tell anybody,” he said, “but I am Dr. Einstein, I’m on my way home, and I’ve forgotten where my house is.”
Thinking, in safety
Over the past years, I’ve made a habit of having at least one long walk / hike every weekend. I take immense joy - if I happen to go by myself and I’m not actively listening to an audio book or am concentrating on some task - to just wander around and immerse myself in random thoughts, think about hard problems, strategise, and attempt to arrive at sound conclusions. This mental wandering, almost like a meditation, I am sure that happens for most of us, in several instances. Maybe when waking up, during the shower, during a walk, during a boring talk, when contemplating art or nature, etc.
Since we are not omniscient and omnipresent, we have several limitations in knowing how a given action will translate into a set of consequences, so we use probabilistic models and heuristics in our thought processes to discern which are the most likely actions that will help us arrive at a desirable outcome. And the more relevant information and time we have to process our thoughts, the better our results will be.
In all of these, I believe there is one common denominator that is fundamental for that process to happen: safety.
The influence of one’s environment
Let’s assume you live with access to information and resources (food, money, shelter, etc), but are living in a situation where your surrounding environment requires you to keep alert and attentive to hazard to your physical / mental wellbeing, or you are in a situation where your social stability is dependent on incapacitating amounts of your energy and time. This could be due to living in a dangerous neighborhood, having overly demanding peers, an abusive household, etc.
Even though there might be a series of limited actions one could take to improve their situation, the constant fight-or-flight severely restricts the opportunities where these action plans can be considered, which eventually leads to reactive actions that could have a number of possible outcomes (good or bad), rather than surgical long term actions that would pave the path towards positive outcomes.
The takeaway
While many many situations are not under our control, such as our initial conditions, birth place, etc, which place a default upper bound on any possible outcomes, we do have agency over some parts of our life, and that is what we can focus on. The path to unwanted consequences is a slippery slope made of several small decisions, some under our control, others not. But for the ones we have the opportunity to control, we should.
For example, the peers one choses to have around, the choice to avoid short term pleasures that have a high long term cost, the choice of which country or neighborhood to live in, the choice of which job offer to strive for, etc.
Do notice that the italics are intentional. The choices above assume that those are options you have under your control to pick, which I am conscious that is not always the case.]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/06/09/aloof.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>让我给你讲一个故事</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/05/05/let-me-tell-you-a-story.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/05/05/let-me-tell-you-a-story.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>禁止将手机带出卧室</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/04/01/banishing_mobile_phones_from_bedroom.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/04/01/banishing_mobile_phones_from_bedroom.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>极简主义 Onyx BOOX Note Air3 黑白版设置</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/03/25/minimalist_boox.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/03/25/minimalist_boox.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>马斯克的传记：为什么它如此有趣</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/02/18/elon_musk_biography.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/02/18/elon_musk_biography.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>项目规划框架</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/01/27/project_planning_framework.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2024/01/27/project_planning_framework.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>让模因超越其宿主</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2023/12/31/meme-transcending-host.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2023/12/31/meme-transcending-host.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>纽约市指南</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2023/12/25/nyc.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2023/12/25/nyc.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>人工智能时代的工作安全</title>
      <link>https://lopespm.com/notes/2023/12/25/job_safety_in_ai_era.html</link>
      <description><![CDATA[文字很便宜，而且越来越便宜。本博客的最后几篇笔记可能是通过生成式人工智能编写的，随着时间的推移，新的生成模型可能会持续创造出比我所能制作的更高质量的内容。
我没有使用这些，因为写作过程是一种思考，但如果有自动化机制在许多不同领域越来越胜过我们人类，那我们还能剩下什么呢？
人际关系
与一个比你聪明和有能力几个数量级的人建立关系，你会感到多么舒服？不仅仅是逻辑数学智能，还有情感、语言、音乐甚至空间智能。
一种如此先进的生物，你和它之间的任何形式的交流或关系都会受到严重限制，即使有神经接口也是如此。一种如此先进的生物，你永远无法对它有基本的了解。一种如此先进的生物，你甚至不知道你被它操纵了。你知道有多少人与我们最亲近的亲戚黑猩猩或倭黑猩猩是朋友？
我们仍然是人类，拥有随之而来的所有好处和局限性。
我认为人类总是会被他们熟悉的同类所吸引。其他生物与他们有着相同的挣扎和局限性，因此，他们也会创造和分享。机器在世界上占有重要地位，历史已经向我们证明，随着技术的发展为我们服务，整个生活都在改善，但将它们视为工具而不是人类的替代品对我们来说会更健康。
生物工程
我们拥有非凡的感官和工具，使我们能够有效地与世界互动。大自然花了很长时间才塑造了我们，正如列奥纳多·达·芬奇在比较自然结构和人工结构时所说：“大自然创造了最完美的发明。没有多余的东西，也没有缺少的东西”（释义）
我们的地方
试着让机器修理浴室漏水的管道，或者更换办公桌的灯泡。很有可能在不久的将来，你会被洪水淹没，陷入黑暗之中。将来有一天，它们很可能会做到这一点，但我们还没有做到这一点。
目前，机器/工具在数字领域的几项任务以及几项重型物理任务中的表现都优于我们。但在精细的数字灵活性、人际交往以及与现实世界及其复杂性的互动方面，我们仍然具有优势。
面向未来
看看你工作中的日常任务。它们有多重复？如果是重复的，有多少人为因素？看看你的组织，看看在人际关系和物理干预方面，橡胶与道路的接触点。
努力更接近人机界面，并专注于为人们或企业（人群）提供有形价值。有了这种简单的心态，我相信你会处于一个更安全的地方，周围有丰富的有意义的价值（金钱、情感等），你可以提取和提供这些价值。]]></description>
      <guid>https://lopespm.com/notes/2023/12/25/job_safety_in_ai_era.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>