<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Robb Knight • 帖子 • Atom Feed</title>
    <link>https://rknight.me/subscribe/posts/atom.xml</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 18:23:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>我曾是 Conduit 的嘉宾</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/i-was-a-guest-on-conduit/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[几周前，Jay 联系我，问我是否愿意做 Conduit 的嘉宾，我当然立刻答应了。
我们谈到了我的部分项目，包括我正在使用 EchoFeed 做什么，然后我被要求[1]创建一个网站，我做到了。在超级指挥家节目结束后，杰伊问我关于英国汽车的问题，我不得不把我从 Top Gear 和 Grand Tour 上学到的所有知识都用上。
听听 Conduit 91：Robb Knight 为自己做了这个，也许你也一样



这不是一个挑战，但我把它当作一个挑战⤾


]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/i-was-a-guest-on-conduit/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 17:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>我多久没看过《贱女孩》了？</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/how-long-since-i-watched-mean-girls-/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/how-long-since-i-watched-mean-girls-/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 16:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lens：元标签检查器（Robb 版本）</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/lens-meta-tag-checker-robbs-version/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/lens-meta-tag-checker-robbs-version/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:53:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>表情符号风暴</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/emojistorm/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[你知道吗，有时候你做了一件事，然后你想“哦，我要做另一件事”，然后又做了另一件与此相关的事情，然后你知道你正在用别人做的一个网络组件制作一个奇怪的网站，因为你可以？不是吗？不管怎样。
EmojiStorm 就是这样一个项目。它以 Zach 的 snow-fall 组件 的一个实例开始，然后你可以继续添加更多，但这是一个随机的表情符号。
十个左右之后，它会变得有点慢，这取决于你的电脑，所以你已经被警告了。
在这里查看 EmojiStorm。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/emojistorm/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 21:22:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>鸡肉丁加食谱</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/chicken-tinga-recipe/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[自从我上周第一次做这个以来，我就一直在想这个食谱。它来自Brian Lagerstrom，他是我最喜欢的 YouTube 厨师。我对这个食谱做了一些不同的修改，但它与他的食谱基本相同，如果你想看视频，他可以满足你的要求。
我用的是商店买的扁面包，它们很美味，但我很想找到一个好用、简单的扁面包食谱。如果有人有，请告诉我。








我更喜欢扁面包，而不是脆脆的玉米饼或墨西哥卷饼，所以我用扁面包来做。我喜欢这些 Deli Kitchen 产品。
原始食谱要求用酸奶油和酸橙搅拌，但谁有时间呢。单独使用酸奶油就可以了。
我用几茶匙预先切碎的大蒜代替自己切片。
来源

1.2 公斤 鸡大腿油1 切碎的洋葱3 瓣 切片大蒜盐25g 番茄酱400g 晒干的番茄/烤辣椒2 大块番茄200g 鸡汤50g 墨西哥辣椒酱5g 盐20g 苹果醋扁面包小宝石生菜酸奶油手持搅拌机
将烤箱预热至 200°c/400°f。
将鸡大腿放在烤盘上。在两面撒上适量盐，放入烤箱烤25 分钟。
在平底锅中加入油、切碎的洋葱、切片大蒜和盐，中火煎5 分钟。
在平底锅中加入番茄酱，搅拌均匀，煎2-3 分钟。
加入晒干的番茄/火烤辣椒、大块切碎的将番茄、鸡汤和墨西哥辣椒酱倒入锅中。小火煮10-15 分钟，直到汤汁变稠，新鲜番茄煮熟。 
加入盐和苹果醋，然后用浸入式搅拌机搅拌至顺滑。
用手将鸡肉撕碎，然后将其与酱汁混合。
将扁面包轻轻烤一下，在每个扁面包上加入一汤匙鸡肉丁，加入一些切碎的小宝石生菜，淋上酸奶油。

]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/chicken-tinga-recipe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 12:59:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>链接转储 #5</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/link-dump-5/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ React, CMS, Bluesky, Eleventy, Kagi总结:文章中介绍了多个技术工具和资源。首先有对React及其不尽如人意的表现的批评。接下来提到了几位作者尝试使用Bluesky PDS的体验，以及Eleventy的一篇入门教程推荐。此外，讨论了Kagi搜索引擎在处理订阅内容时显示出的高效性。最后，作者表达了对某些视频游戏和网页视频资源的兴趣，并提到了一种理想的静态站点CMS的想法。 
Time for a heaving link dump becuase I&#39;m well into triple figures in my Raindrop inbox.
First up are a pair of intorductions: one to Alpine.js by Blake of HTML for People fame and one for htmx. I&#39;m always on the lookout for something a bit less complicated than a full-on framework.
Things you forgot (or never knew) because of React is a scathing look at the state[1] of React in comparison to other, similar frameworks and it&#39;s not great.
Ergonomic Static Site Blogging. Someone else on a quest to have a nice CMS for a static site with no success.
Leon and Melanie both wrote up their experience with Coolify with the latter setting up a Bluesky PDS for shits and giggles[2]:

The hardest part of all of this was Bluesky’s instability. Bluesky likes to pretend that it is “decentralized” or “federated.” It sure as shit isn’t either of those things.

How I teach Eleventy from scratch is an excellent intro to Eleventy by Juha-Matti; this will be my go-to next time someone asks about how to get started.
One more tutorial, this time for CSS sprite sheet animations.
Coding Font sets up a bracket like the sports do to choose the best coding font for you. It lacks a few popular ones but it&#39;s a fun distraction for a couple of minutes.
Kagi, the search engine, open-sourced their feed parser. &quot;It&#39;s 10x-100x faster than a traditional feedparser&quot;.
Can I PHP? It&#39;s like Can I Use but for PHP features. Fun.
I was wronged by Safari and was sent this great post on browsers by Tyler. Also, it&#39;s not just me.
Gamery released ScanDex, a &quot;curated barcode database for video games&quot; and Foursquare released a huge places dataset.
I don&#39;t have much call for doing web videos but player.style look likes a great resource for different styles.
Johnny mentioned he used Migadu Email for his email. Pricing looks great, unlimited domains and mailboxes. If I ever need to move off of iCloud, this might be the way to go.
“Back to the Future” and “The Goonies” take place on the same day. Can&#39;t argue with this logic, it&#39;s canon now.
I am obsessed with Wes Tank Rapping Fox in Socks on the Dr Suess channel.
An Akaline Trio font.
And finally, I want this clothes shop for dads idea to be a reality.

you&#39;re sure as hell not gonna advertise some bugger else&#39;s T-shirt business on your body, so you give him twelve quid and he hands you Bin Bag 2




Not an intentional pun ⤾

or more likely, through genuine curiousity ⤾


]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/link-dump-5/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 12:06:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>应用默认设置 2024</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/app-defaults-2024/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ RSS, Raindrop, Mastodon, BBC新闻, 提醒总结:一年来我的生活发生了很多变化。我目前完全使用来处理待办事项，尽管觉得提醒功能有些烦人。我自己托管RSS，并在iOS上使用，在Mac上使用。关于书签，我选择了自托管的解决方案。至于稍后阅读，我使用Raindrop，以前用的Omnivore已经停用了。在新闻方面，我仍在使用Mastodon，但应建议已将BBC新闻从我的主屏幕上移除。 
It&#39;s been just over a year since Dual of the Defaults burst into our lives and my time was consumed by tracking nearly 400 blog posts. Rather than write out last years list again, here&#39;s what has changed since then:
To-Do: I&#39;m all in on Godspeed. Reminders is just a bit...annoying?
RSS: Self-hosted Miniflux with Reeder Classic on iOS and NetNewsWire on the Mac. Reeder is new because it has a dark icon, NetNewsWire doesn&#39;t right now.
Bookmarks: Self-hosted LinkAce.
Read-it-Later: Raindrop. Ominvore as it happens is now gone but I switched a while ago.
News: I&#39;m still using Mastodon but on the advice of Johnny, BBC news is gone from my home screen.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/app-defaults-2024/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:18:38 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>在 Coolify 上安装 GoToSocial</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/installing-gotosocial-on-coolify/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[由于各种原因，我今晚有机会尝试一下 GoToSocial，所以我将它安装在运行 Coolify 的服务器上，但遇到了几个问题，在 Lewis 和 Brandon 的帮助下，我解决了这些问题。
首先，因为它运行的是反向代理，所以我需要 Docker compose 文件中的第三个选项。
端口： # - “443:8080” ## 对于 letsencrypt： #- “80:80” ## 对于反向代理设置： - “127.0.0.1:8082:8080”
第二个问题是 GoToSocial 无法访问数据库，日志中显示此错误：
sqlite ping：sqlite3：无法打开数据库文件
此 GitHub 问题显示这是一个权限问题，其中 docker compose 中指定的用户不是具有 gotosocial/data 文件权限的用户。我本可以尝试找出用户和组是什么，或者我可以通过 chmod 来解决这个问题。猜猜我选了哪一个。在 Coolify 中，转到侧边栏中的 Terminal，选择安装 GoToSocial 的项目，然后连接并 cd 到目录。然后设置数据目录的权限。
$ cd /data/coolify/services/isjdbvfihsavfids/$ chmod 777 gotosocial/data
我通过检查 Coolify 中 GoToSocial 服务上的 storage 选项卡获得了它的安装目录 (/isjdbvfihsavfids)。
其他说明：

/settings 可让您进入帐户的设置页面。
帖子的默认可见性为“未列出”，与 Mastodon 不同，Mastodon 的公开可见性为默认。您可以在设置中更改此设置。
其他实例级设置（如配置文件上的自定义 CSS）可以在 config.yaml 文件中更改，请参阅此处的配置文档。
将用户设为管理员需要重新启动服务器。

我仍在尝试使用 GoToSocial，但它看起来是我想要的一个很好的解决方案 - 比 Mastodon 更容易维护，资源占用更少。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/installing-gotosocial-on-coolify/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 21:00:33 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>阻止 Mastodon 获取我的笔记的元数据</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/stopping-mastodon-from-fetching-metadata-for-my-notes/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/stopping-mastodon-from-fetching-metadata-for-my-notes/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 13:34:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>有用的 Bluesky 工具</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/useful-bluesky-tools/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[这个周末，我一直在帮助在 Bluesky 上设置 MacStories，并且我偶然发现了一些方便的网站。GitHub 上的这个 awesome-bluesky 列表中有很多有趣的与 Bluesky 相关的链接，下面是我偶然发现并觉得有用的链接。
ClearSky 允许您查看您位于哪些列表（启动包）、您屏蔽了谁以及谁屏蔽了您。顺便说一句，屏蔽数据是公开的并且没有办法选择退出启动包，这表明完全没有考虑到这可能会被滥用，但这不是这篇文章的重点。不太重要，但为什么入门包的最低要求是七个这让我很难过。
我发现了两个用于解析 DID 的工具，您需要它们来处理各种与 API 相关的事情。DID 是“每个帐户的持久、长期标识符。”它们看起来像这样：did:plc:b3i7xuqiybecdpm3lkywmlwv。

Bluesky DID 解析器
Bluesky DID 生成器 - 令人困惑的是，它被命名为“生成器”

要在 Ivory 等 Mastodon 客户端中使用 Bluesky，您可以使用 Skybridge。如果我不能使用 Ivory，我怀疑我是否会检查 Bluesky。我使用 Coolify 自行安装了它。不过，Deck Blue 是一款不错的 Web 客户端。
最后，SkyLink 是一款 Chrome 扩展程序，与 Streetpass 类似（尽管不那么先进）。
您可以在 MacStories 入门包 中查看所有 MacStories 团队和播客帐户，我在那里的用户名是 @rknight.me。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/useful-bluesky-tools/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 15:15:19 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>本周我是 AppStories 的嘉宾</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/i-was-a-guest-on-appstories-this-week/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ MacStories, AppStories+, fediverse, ActivityPub, development setup总结:最近几周MacStories每周都邀请不同的主持人，这周轮到作者亲自参与。在AppStories+的预展中，他们讨论了节目的起源；在正式节目中，他们探讨了fediverse和ActivityPub，分享了作者的一些开发设置。节目最后，还有一段关于主持人Federico对作者人格的看法，这让作者感到震惊。你可以选择用你喜欢的播客软件收听这一集，或者观看视频版本。 
The past few weeks AppStories has had a different MacStories host as a guest and this week was my turn. In the AppStories+ pre-show we talk about the origins of Ruminate and in the main show we discuss the fediverse and ActivityPub, some of my projects, as well as my development setup. Stick around to find out what kind of person Federico thinks I am because I&#39;m still reeling.
Listen to episode 412: What Kind of Person Are You? in your podcatcher of choice or you can watch the episode on YouTube.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/i-was-a-guest-on-appstories-this-week/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 12:52:40 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>水牛城辣酱食谱</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/buffalo-sauce-recipe/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 辣酱、大蒜、辣椒酱、黄油、食醋总结:这是一个制作水牛城辣酱的食谱。首先将辣酱、切碎的大蒜、辣椒酱和食醋放入锅中，用中高火加热并搅拌，煮5分钟直至略为浓稠。然后降低火力，慢慢加入无盐黄油搅拌均匀。最后，在离火后加入少许黄原胶使辣酱更加稠密。整个过程简单快捷，适合喜欢辣味的人尝试。 
I don&#39;t know where I got this recipe but it&#39;s buffalo sauce so I suspect it&#39;s mostly the same from everyone but here we are, final day of recipe week. Enjoy.







Buffalo Sauce
300g Hot Sauce4 Garlic Gloves20g Worcestershire Sauce15g Distilled Vinegar120g Unsalted Butter
Add hot sauce, garlic gloves, worcestershire sauce, and distilled vinegar to sauce pan over medium high heat. Whisk ingredients together and allow to cook for 5 minutes until thickened slightly. Whisk in the unsalted butter slowly on low heat. A tiny pinch of Xantham gum once it&#39;s off the heat.

]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/buffalo-sauce-recipe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 21:07:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>韭菜培根烤土豆食谱</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/leek-and-bacon-jacket-potatoes-recipe/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 土豆, 培根, 韭菜, 奶油奶酪, 微波炉总结:这是一种美味的夹克土豆制作方法。首先将土豆用微波炉加热15分钟，期间翻转一次。然后在烤箱中继续烘烤土豆。接着将切好的培根在锅中煎至变色，加入韭菜煎2-3分钟，再加入奶油奶酪、黑胡椒和辣椒粉调味搅拌均匀。最后将土豆切半，加入一些黄油和韭菜培根混合物，撒上一些辣椒粉即可食用。 
Day six of Recipe Week. This is certainly not healthy in any way at all but god damn is it tasty.







Leek and Bacon Jacket PotatoesThere are many ways to make a jacket potato, I choose the microwave way because it&#39;s quicker.

2 Jacket potatoes8rashers Chopped Bacon40g Leeks165g Cream CheeseBlack PepperPaprikaButter
Pre-heat the oven to 200°c. 
Jab your jacket potatoes with a fork a handful of times and put in the microwave for 15 minutes, turn halfway through.
Put your jackets in the oven while you make the topping.
Cook the chopped bacon in a pan with a little bit of oil until browned off, then add in leeks and fry those for 2-3 minutes. Turn the heat down and add in cream cheese, black pepper, and paprika, and stir it all together.
Cut your jackets in half, add some butter to them, then top with the leek and bacon topping. Sprinkle some paprika on top to serve.

]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/leek-and-bacon-jacket-potatoes-recipe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 11:33:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>命名我的计算机</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/naming-my-computers/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 设备命名, Marvel角色, iPhone, AirPods, Beats Studio buds总结:本文作者介绍了自己为电子设备命名的方法，其中大部分以Marvel角色为主。例如，他的Mac Mini被命名为J.A.R.V.I.S，MacBook Pro和iPhone尚未提及命名，Apple Watch和AirPods Pro的命名未被透露。而AirPods Max因材质被命名为Metal。此外，作者为Beats Studio buds起了一个与众不同的名字——Fantastic Beats and Where to Find Them，而iPad因使用不频繁而简单地命名为Robb&#39;s iPad。这种命名方式给作者的设备增添了一份个性和趣味。 
Alex has an excellent post about how they name their computers which is, as they mention, a very important part of setting up a new device.
Unlike Alex, I don&#39;t choose a new name when it gets replaced - my iPhone is always called Starlord. Which brings me to the naming scheme: Marvel characters. Some of these make sense, some of them don&#39;t.

Mac Mini: This is used for Plex and some other boring home things but it&#39;s the hub for the house or something. Anyway I went with Jarvis. Technically it&#39;s written J.A.R.V.I.S. but who&#39;s got time for that.
MacBook Pro: This is my main computer and is called Vision.
iPhone: Starlord
Apple Watch: Rocket
AirPods Pro: Maximoff. Because there&#39;s two of them? A clever one.
AirPods Max: Magneto because metal
My black Apple Magic keyboard: Black Widow

My Beats Studio buds are the one exception to this naming rule because I thought of a name[1] so good I couldn&#39;t not use it: Fantastic Beats and Where to Find Them. My iPad is called Robb&#39;s iPad because I don&#39;t use it enough to name it.



I originally thought of this joke for this tweet ⤾


]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/naming-my-computers/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:23:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蟾蜍进洞食谱</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/toad-in-the-hole-recipe/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[好吧，伙计们，这是有史以来最懒惰的“食谱”，但它很棒，所以我们就在这里：蟾蜍在洞里。下次做的时候我会拍一张更好的照片，我不得不从我的 Instagram/Pixelfed 档案中取出这张照片。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/toad-in-the-hole-recipe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 09:29:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>