<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Robb Knight • 帖子 • Atom Feed</title>
    <link>https://rknight.me/subscribe/posts/atom.xml</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 12:33:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>韭菜培根烤土豆食谱</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/leek-and-bacon-jacket-potatoes-recipe/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 土豆, 培根, 韭菜, 奶油奶酪, 微波炉总结:这是一种美味的夹克土豆制作方法。首先将土豆用微波炉加热15分钟，期间翻转一次。然后在烤箱中继续烘烤土豆。接着将切好的培根在锅中煎至变色，加入韭菜煎2-3分钟，再加入奶油奶酪、黑胡椒和辣椒粉调味搅拌均匀。最后将土豆切半，加入一些黄油和韭菜培根混合物，撒上一些辣椒粉即可食用。 
Day six of Recipe Week. This is certainly not healthy in any way at all but god damn is it tasty.







Leek and Bacon Jacket PotatoesThere are many ways to make a jacket potato, I choose the microwave way because it&#39;s quicker.

2 Jacket potatoes8rashers Chopped Bacon40g Leeks165g Cream CheeseBlack PepperPaprikaButter
Pre-heat the oven to 200°c. 
Jab your jacket potatoes with a fork a handful of times and put in the microwave for 15 minutes, turn halfway through.
Put your jackets in the oven while you make the topping.
Cook the chopped bacon in a pan with a little bit of oil until browned off, then add in leeks and fry those for 2-3 minutes. Turn the heat down and add in cream cheese, black pepper, and paprika, and stir it all together.
Cut your jackets in half, add some butter to them, then top with the leek and bacon topping. Sprinkle some paprika on top to serve.

]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/leek-and-bacon-jacket-potatoes-recipe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 11:33:13 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>命名我的计算机</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/naming-my-computers/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 设备命名, Marvel角色, iPhone, AirPods, Beats Studio buds总结:本文作者介绍了自己为电子设备命名的方法，其中大部分以Marvel角色为主。例如，他的Mac Mini被命名为J.A.R.V.I.S，MacBook Pro和iPhone尚未提及命名，Apple Watch和AirPods Pro的命名未被透露。而AirPods Max因材质被命名为Metal。此外，作者为Beats Studio buds起了一个与众不同的名字——Fantastic Beats and Where to Find Them，而iPad因使用不频繁而简单地命名为Robb&#39;s iPad。这种命名方式给作者的设备增添了一份个性和趣味。 
Alex has an excellent post about how they name their computers which is, as they mention, a very important part of setting up a new device.
Unlike Alex, I don&#39;t choose a new name when it gets replaced - my iPhone is always called Starlord. Which brings me to the naming scheme: Marvel characters. Some of these make sense, some of them don&#39;t.

Mac Mini: This is used for Plex and some other boring home things but it&#39;s the hub for the house or something. Anyway I went with Jarvis. Technically it&#39;s written J.A.R.V.I.S. but who&#39;s got time for that.
MacBook Pro: This is my main computer and is called Vision.
iPhone: Starlord
Apple Watch: Rocket
AirPods Pro: Maximoff. Because there&#39;s two of them? A clever one.
AirPods Max: Magneto because metal
My black Apple Magic keyboard: Black Widow

My Beats Studio buds are the one exception to this naming rule because I thought of a name[1] so good I couldn&#39;t not use it: Fantastic Beats and Where to Find Them. My iPad is called Robb&#39;s iPad because I don&#39;t use it enough to name it.



I originally thought of this joke for this tweet ⤾


]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/naming-my-computers/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:23:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蟾蜍进洞食谱</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/toad-in-the-hole-recipe/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[好吧，伙计们，这是有史以来最懒惰的“食谱”，但它很棒，所以我们就在这里：蟾蜍在洞里。下次做的时候我会拍一张更好的照片，我不得不从我的 Instagram/Pixelfed 档案中取出这张照片。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/toad-in-the-hole-recipe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 09:29:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>更多关于 Bluesky 的杂乱想法</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/more-unorganised-thoughts-about-bluesky/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Bluesky, 自托管, 储存空间, ActivityPub, 骚扰总结:文章讨论了Bluesky平台及其与其他社交媒体的对比，尤其是技术实现和使用Bluesky的理由。自托管Bluesky较复杂，需要4.5TB的存储空间，远超单一PHP文件的可能性。同时提到Bluesky可能是Twitter的简化替代品，而Fediverse作为去中心化的跨平台连接器。在Mastodon平台上，边缘化群体面临骚扰的情况被提及，这也是一些人选择Bluesky的原因之一。作者最后考虑自己托管PDS，以便在需要时更容易地管理数据。 
I got a lot of feedback from my last post which fell into two categories: either about the technical implementations or why someone is using Bluesky over other options. As soon as my sent my previous post Bluesky started having outages which has made looking into the feedback interesting to say the least but they&#39;ve been adding obscene amounts of users every second today.
Technical
MCG and Matt linked me to this post which is titled &quot;How to self-host all of Bluesky except the AppView (for now)&quot;. There are more components to self-hosting Bluesky than say, Mastodon, but it is doable. Sort of. You can&#39;t do the AppView which &quot;aggregates data from across the Atmosphere to produce their UIs&quot;. It&#39;s late and I don&#39;t have the energy to translate what that actually means but it sounds important.
The part that jumped out to me (after MCG mentioned it) is the article mentions needing 4.5tb of storage for the relay which is a fuckton and might as well be a million terabytes for the sake of discussing self-hosting. There is a second relay option called Jetstream which from my reading of it, can be used instead of the 4.5tb version. Looking at the docs it&#39;s not ideal for all circumstances but if we assume it could work for a small user base then cool. This is, however, a far stretch from my question of could it be done on a single PHP file. Seems like that&#39;s going to be a no. ActivityPub is by no means simple but AT Proto seems infinitely more complicated.
Why use it?
The why is harder. There&#39;s no accounting for what people like or enjoy, people just do. A lot of it came down to just a feeling of what Bluesky is like (early Twitter was banded around a bit).
Friend of the show Alex Cox pointed out to me, a cis white dude, that marginalised people on Mastodon are subject to constant reply guys and harassment. I&#39;m embarrassed that I didn&#39;t even think of it.

Most marginalized people who joined mastodon.social or another generic instance bounced pretty quickly because not many want to stick around and learn how to create your own instance when in the meantime you’re constantly blocking random guys telling you you’re doing it/everything wrong

As an aside, most of the reports we deal with on social.lol are spam probably because the instance is paid so there&#39;s a barrier that doesn&#39;t exist on mastodon.social and the other big instances.
Final Thoughts
Ben has a great post here about Bluesky, the Fediverse, and the future of social media:

Bluesky may evolve into a streamlined alternative to Twitter, while the Fediverse could serve as a decentralized, cross-platform connector among diverse networks

There&#39;s no reason to believe both can&#39;t continue to exist side by side. Mastodon isn&#39;t going anywhere and if better tools for self hosting come around for Bluesky, I could see myself potentially using both.
This is too much for one person to think about protocols[1] but I do want to investigate hosting a PDS if only because my data could be deleted easily by me without relying on Bluesky to do so if something were to happen. I think this is the case although I suppose it&#39;d be in other relays? Something to look into.



Especially after last week&#39;s recipe saga ⤾


]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/more-unorganised-thoughts-about-bluesky/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 21:50:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>关于蓝天的杂乱想法</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/unorganised-thoughts-about-bluesky/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Bluesky, API, Starter Packs, Mastodon, 交叉发布总结:这篇文章主要记录了作者对社交网络Bluesky的一些初步感受和思考。首先，作者觉得Bluesky的API设计相对其他社交网络来说比较奇异，开发者需要手动标记话题、提及和链接，并且需要自己处理链接预览。作者也提到了Bluesky的Starter Packs功能虽然受到了一部分人的喜爱，但他本人更倾向于用户能够通过浏览内容后再做关注决定。此外，作者对比了Bluesky和Mastodon，不太理解为什么有人会从Mastodon转到Bluesky。最后，作者还提到了自己如何通过交叉发布保持与粉丝的互动，并且他对社交平台的交互持开放态度。 
These thoughts about Bluesky are unorganised and mostly off-the-cuff so make of that what you will.
The API, even just for posting, strikes me as very strange. I, as the developer, have to mark which things are hashtags, mentions, and links unlike Twitter, Mastodon, and basically every other network. If I want link previews I have to do that too.
The Personal Data Store is interesting. I haven&#39;t set one up but Brandon and Rafael did and it seems easy enough but this is just one part of the AT Protocol. Is it possible to host the entire stack yourself without relying on bsky.social? Can you be part of the AT Protocol with a single PHP file? That might sound stupid but I don&#39;t think that&#39;s an unreasonable bar to interact with a network even if it&#39;s in a limited way.
Starter Packs are a good idea that people seem to like but I would rather people followed me because they&#39;ve had a gander at what I post and decided to follow. Choosing to follow people en masse without looking at those profiles seems weird to me. The other thing is it feels like they pigeon-hole people into being a specific version of themselves and perhaps give unrealistic expectations to people following[1]. I feel the same about mastodon instances focused around a specific topic.
I&#39;ve seen a few people drop Mastodon for Bluesky but I don&#39;t really understand why, nothing about it jumps out at me as all that different to Mastodon. You have to go where your people are though so it could just be that. I&#39;m pretty sure Bluesky will get enshittified before too long and everyone will be onto the next thing.
I am cross-posting my posts and links to my Bluesky account with EchoFeed. People are there, they presumably followed me to see my things, and I don&#39;t lose anything if the service blows up overnight. POSSE, baby.
I setup my own install of SkyBridge so I can use Ivory to read my Bluesky timeline because none of the apps are as good as Ivory and probably never will be.
I&#39;ve updated my verify page to reflect the fact that I am using Bluesky.



&quot;Stop posting about politics, stay in your lane&quot; ⤾


]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/unorganised-thoughts-about-bluesky/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 17:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>熨斗通心粉奶酪食谱</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/flatiron-mac-and-cheese-recipe/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 纽约, 阿里, 生活, 鹿子酒会, 威尔士乡村总结:文章讲述了作者的朋友阿里在纽约生活时曾尝试过的一道菜谱，并在不同场合包括作者的鹿子酒会上为朋友们烹制。提到鹿子酒会是在威尔士乡村的一间小屋中，三个朋友共度了三天的美好时光。 
This recipe came to me via my friend Ali, who had it at The Flatiron Room when he was living in New York. He&#39;s made it for us a bunch of times, including on my stag do, as you can in the accompanying photo.
As an aside, my stag do was three of us in a cabin in the middle of the Welsh countryside for three days and it was glorious.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/flatiron-mac-and-cheese-recipe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>芝士鸡肉培根意面食谱</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/cheesy-chicken-and-bacon-pasta-recipe/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[第三周的食​​谱是奶酪鸡肉培根意面，我上周第一次尝试，味道很棒。你应该试试。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/cheesy-chicken-and-bacon-pasta-recipe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 11:55:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蜜饯墨西哥胡椒食谱</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/candied-jalapenos-recipe/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[食谱周的第二天是这个蜜饯墨西哥胡椒食谱，我喜欢在夏天开始时做一批，用在我的 Ooni 上的披萨上。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/candied-jalapenos-recipe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>芒果咖喱鸡食谱</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/mango-chicken-curry-recipe/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[正如上周所承诺的那样，本周是食谱周。
这是我们每隔几周为 Baby Knight 批量烹饪的一道菜，她吃得非常过瘾。上一批菜我没有番茄酱，但我还是继续做了，她仍然很喜欢。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/mango-chicken-curry-recipe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 08:54:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>为 Eleventy Three Ways 添加 Cooklang 支持</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/adding-cooklang-support-to-eleventy-two-ways/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/adding-cooklang-support-to-eleventy-two-ways/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 08:37:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>为什么没有人使用食谱模式？</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/why-is-no-one-using-the-recipe-schema/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/why-is-no-one-using-the-recipe-schema/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 08:47:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>对食谱格式的思考比任何人都要多</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/thinking-about-recipe-formats-more-than-anyone-should/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/thinking-about-recipe-formats-more-than-anyone-should/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 20:23:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>我们有家庭第二季</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/we-got-family-season-two/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
We Got Family 是我和 David Darnes 合作制作的关于《速度与激情》系列电影的播客。第一季我们制作了前四部电影，外加一集Superfast!。
好久不见，我们回来继续制作第二季，从 2011 年的《速度与激情 5》开始。 在网站上收听，也可以通过RSS、Apple Podcasts、Spotify、Overcast、Pocketcasts、卡斯特罗，或者您获取播客的任何地方。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/we-got-family-season-two/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>博客PoMo AMA</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/weblogpomo-ama/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/weblogpomo-ama/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 10:32:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>使用 Setapp</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/using-setapp/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[自从 2017 年推出以来，我一直关注着 Setapp，但对我来说，一直没有合适的时机加入......直到本周。我真的想使用 Setapp 上的 Godspeed（以及独立订阅），所以我做了一些计算，看看它是否值得。
我从我知道我肯定会使用的东西开始：

Godspeed - 每年 48 美元
Dropshare - 版本 5 的生命周期内一次性 39 美元。为此，我假设每隔几年就会有一个新版本，所以每年 20 美元
Cleanshot X - 一年更新 29 美元
TablePlus - 一年 89 美元更新

如果我将这些加起来并除以 12，则每月费用为 15.50 美元。我想要 Godspeed、Awesome Habits 和 Soulver 的 iOS 选项（见下文），这样 Setapp 每月的费用为 15 美元（含税）。因此，基本上是收支平衡 - 我可以通过按年付费让 Setapp 更便宜，但目前我坚持按月付费。该价格还不包括我会使用的其他应用程序，因为它们是可用的。一些我过去想使用的应用程序，但无法证明我的使用价格是合理的：

ToothFairy。这是 Blake 推荐的，因为我遇到了一个愚蠢的问题。
Soulver。我一直在使用 Numi，但 Soulver 的功能更多，而且还有 iOS 版本
Downie。yt-dl 很棒，但我更喜欢 GUI 来完成这种事情。
Paletro。非常方便。
Clean My Mac。不知怎的，这为我节省了 50GB 的空间。绝对值得。
很棒的习惯。我当时正在关注 Streaks，但 MacStoried 的一些工作人员推荐了 Awesome Habits

还有一些其他的也不错，但我绝对不会用到需要直接付费的：

Mockuuups Studio
Typeface
HandMirror
ClearVPN
Structured
Squash

因此，如果我使用这些附加应用程序，哪怕只是少数几个，我也能省钱。这不是无法承受不订阅的情况，但对我来说，这是一笔相当划算的交易。
Setapp...应用程序本身只是一个应用商店。您可以查看热门下载、新应用程序、合集，将应用程序标记为收藏，并且它有特定应用程序的指南。默认情况下，它会在菜单栏中放置一个图标，但您可以将其关闭，因为它除了打开应用程序外不执行任何操作。
iOS 端涉及从 App Store 下载任何应用程序，然后扫描二维码以验证您是否订阅了 Setapp。这是一种有趣的处理方式，我不知道 Apple 的愚蠢规则是如何允许这样做的，但我不会继续讨论这个问题。
显然，基于上述内容，我省了钱，但我很好奇应用程序开发人员从中得到了什么样的优惠。事实证明，Setapp 对其帮助文档上的工作原理非常透明：

我们与特定用户使用的应用程序的开发人员分享每位用户费用的 70%

还有关于额外 20%“给带来该特定用户的合作伙伴”的内容。我不知道这意味着什么，但这对开发人员来说似乎是一笔不错的交易。我的钱不会只存入一个资金池，然后支付给最受欢迎的应用程序，而是基于我的真实使用情况。我对这个设置感觉很好。
最后，他们还有一个非常慷慨的推荐计划[1]，这给了我和注册的人一个月的免费使用权。因此，如果您想注册，请使用我的推荐链接获得一个月的免费使用权。



我喜欢好的推荐计划 ⤾


]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/using-setapp/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 20:09:57 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>