<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Robb Knight • 帖子 • Atom Feed</title>
    <link>https://rknight.me/subscribe/posts/atom.xml</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 12:35:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>罗布更好</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/the-robb-jobb/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 。 
今天早上，当我观看这个关于用 Monster 酿酒的视频[1]时，我心想我只想尝试一下，我想知道这是否可以作为 The Robb Jobb 能量饮料部分的替代品。什么是 Robb Jobb？好问题，聪明的读者。 Robb Jobb 是我自己设计的潘趣酒，过去十年里我做过几次，最后一次是在 2020 年的单身派对上。每次大家都说它很好吃，然后就一片混乱。
&quot;Robb，我想现在就做这个，给我食谱&quot;。好吧，冷静下来。和所有好的食谱一样，它有一个说明：把所有这些混合在一起。最好用勺子从桶里或大得可笑的潘趣酒碗里盛出来。

2 升伏特加。
1 升能量饮料。我过去用过 Tesco Blue Spark，但你可以选择任何你喜欢的能量饮料。或者用 Monster 葡萄酒制作，然后告诉我效果如何。
500 毫升啤酒。我更喜欢喜力啤酒。
100 毫升青柠甜酒。

如果您制作或饮用此酒，我不承担任何责任。但它很美味。



必须在 Monster 地区制作，否则它只是起泡能量酒。⤾


]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/the-robb-jobb/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 12:47:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MagSafe 杂项</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/magsafe-miscellania/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 。 
上周我问过是否有人对 MagSafe 车载支架有什么建议，我得到了很多建议。很多人喜欢 Peak Design，但我不会花那么多钱来固定我的手机。很多人还推荐了亚马逊上各种无名品牌的产品，对我来说更容易接受。
我最终选择了这家名为 Lisen 的公司的产品。它可以直接粘在仪表盘上，不会晃动，并且支持 15W 充电（我买了一个点烟器适配器）。
因为过去几年 Apple 的硅胶保护壳一直在我身上散架，所以几年来我一直在购买 Ali Express 上最便宜的保护壳，但我拥有的保护壳都不兼容 MagSafe。这意味着我要翻阅无数页各种灰色保护壳，还有一些看起来就像工厂里刚刚通过了颜色审核的保护壳。我只想要一些好玩的东西。橙色！霓虹绿！粉红色！
如果您想要 MagSafe，这些产品很少见，但我偶然发现了非常有名的 GaoBao 强磁 iPhone 14 Pro 保护壳，超薄 14 Pro 手机壳，兼容 MagSafe 经典防震半透明哑光保护手机壳，适用于 iPhone 14 Pro 6.1&quot; 2022，粉红色。它有多粉？没有比粉红色更粉红的了：

它远非质量最好的手机壳，但它确实有用。还请注意相机周围看似随机的“100% 焦点像素”。这他妈到底是什么意思？
我按照说明将支架安装在车上，然后放置 24 小时，效果非常好。我可以取下手机，而不必担心将支架撕掉，它可以旋转和伸展，这样我就可以把它放在我需要的确切位置，粉色外壳也能正常工作。
MagSafe 相当不错。我只晚了四年。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/magsafe-miscellania/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 12:08:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>我的第一辆车使用时间比利兹·特拉斯担任首相的时间还短</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/my-first-car-lasted-less-time-than-liz-truss-did-as-prime-minister/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 。最后不要加在其中的内容。 
十天前，我通过了驾驶考试，我爸爸很好心地给了我妈妈的旧车：一辆 2011 款 Smart Fortwo。我的计划是，在第二个宝贝骑士出生前，我会开这辆车几个月，然后我们把它换掉，换一辆更大的车，然后我会开我妻子的车。
这是一辆奇怪的车。它的内部空间比你想象的要大得多，后备箱和你想象的一样小，车轮很小，所以你能感觉到每一个颠簸，它是自动的，但不是一台好的自动挡汽车。每次换档都很笨重。但驾驶它还是有趣的。
为了通过驾驶考试，我急于通过考试，其中一部分原因是每周开着第一个宝贝骑士去她祖父母家，这样我的妻子就不必太早去。我需要禁用前排乘客安全气囊，这样我才能把 Baby Knight 放进去，所以我查阅了手册，这似乎很容易：将钥匙插入此开关，将其关闭。但我没有开关 - 经过大量的谷歌搜索后，我发现我想要的开关是一个可选的附加功能，新购买它的人决定不购买。我可以将其关闭，但从我读到的内容来看，如果我想再次启用它，我需要让梅赛德斯重新编码汽车（无论这意味着什么）。
Baby Knight 本周开始上幼儿园，所以我们加快了时间表，买了一辆新车，我们今天取了车，并把智能车作为押金交给了新车。它持续了十天。
再见 Felicia。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/my-first-car-lasted-less-time-than-liz-truss-did-as-prime-minister/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 20:39:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>圣裘德 2024</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/st-jude-2024/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 。

Here is the Chinese summary with key points and format as requested:

儿童癌症 筹款活动 贴纸 omg.lol St Jude

总结:
1. 9月是儿童癌症意识月,即将开始年度筹款活动
2. 去年筹集了一定金额,今年目标是超越这个数字
3. 提供两款独家贴纸:Party Prami和Ruminate Heatwave
4. omg.lol网站提供St Jude主题和支持页脚
5. 每天在某平台上会提供终身omg.lol代码
6. 可以通过指定链接捐款获取贴纸
7. 活动旨在帮助患病儿童 
tl;dr: Donate to our campaign here at stjude.omg.lol.
It&#39;s basically September which means it&#39;s childhood cancer awareness month and time for Relay&#39;s annual fundraising event. Last year, me and Adam raised $12,590.57 as part of the campaign. This year we&#39;re going to try and beat that total and we have two exclusive stickers which you can get for a donation of $15: Party Prami and Ruminate Heatwave.

Over on omg.lol you can use a special St Jude theme for your omg.lol profile which you can see on mine and Adam&#39;s profile. You can also enable a &quot;supporting St Jude&quot; footer for your profile too! Here it all is in action:

Finally, every day on bids.lol they&#39;ll be a lifetime omg.lol code up for grabs and I&#39;m sure Adam has some other tricks up his sleeve.
You can donate at stjude.omg.lol to grab your stickers. It&#39;s for the kids.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/st-jude-2024/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 15:48:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>制定第 10 次接力赛的座位安排</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/building-a-seating-plan-for-relay-10/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/building-a-seating-plan-for-relay-10/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 20:30:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>每个人都可以自由创建网站</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/everybodys-free-to-make-websites/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ couple, re-worked, video, idea, Baz Luhrmann

couple前几天重新制作了Baz Luhrmann著名作品的歌词，后来产生了制作视频的想法。最终制作了一个视频。总结：couple改编了Baz Luhrmann的作品，产生了做视频的想法。 
A couple of days ago Sara tooted, then wrote a post, with re-worked words of the Wear Sunscreen essay made famous by Baz Luhrmann.
Keenan then recorded this over the music and I later had the idea to make a proper video for it, So here it is.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v5UsuZ4DS_Q]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/everybodys-free-to-make-websites/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 07:37:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>获取我的游戏收藏页面的成就和奖杯</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/fetching-achievements-and-trophies-for-my-game-collection-page/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/fetching-achievements-and-trophies-for-my-game-collection-page/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 18:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>使用 Fediverse 创作者标签突出新闻报道</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/highlighting-journalism-with-the-fediverse-creator-tag/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Mastodon, support, author, link, addition

要点: Mastodon 4.3 添加了支持链接作者的功能；这个功能可以通过标签显示作者的资料；第三方客户端可以使用这个数据显示作者信息；该功能目前只适用于经过审核的网站；未来计划将这个功能扩展到所有网站。
总结: Mastodon 4.3添加了支持识别链接作者的功能，这将使用户能够直接跳转到共享链接的作者，非常实用。 
Mastodon 4.3 adds support for a newly proposed OpenGraph tag to identify the creator of the link, which looks like this:
&lt;meta property=&quot;fediverse:creator&quot; content=&quot;@robb@social.lol&quot; /&gt;
Mastodon (and hopefully other places in the future) will use this tag to display the author&#39;s profile below a shared link like so:

This additional data is also included in the card object as authors of the status API so third party clients can use this to display it in their apps as well:
&quot;card&quot;: {	&quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://www.macstories.net/stories/ai-companies-need-to-be-regulated-an-open-letter-to-the-u-s-congress-and-european-parliament/&quot;,&quot;title&quot;: &quot;AI Companies Need to Be Regulated: An Open Letter to the U.S. Congress and European Parliament&quot;,	// the rest of the card data	&quot;authors&quot;: [        {            &quot;account&quot;: {                &quot;id&quot;: &quot;109519808056877508&quot;,                &quot;username&quot;: &quot;johnvoorhees&quot;,                &quot;acct&quot;: &quot;johnvoorhees@macstories.net&quot;,		        // the rest of the author data            }	    }    ]}
I added support for this to MacStories a couple of weeks back for all posts and I&#39;ve added it to my site for when this becomes available for more sites. This won&#39;t work for my site for now though:

the feature will only show up for links to moderator-approved websites. In the future we would like to make the feature available to all without a manual review process

I really like this addition though; being able to jump directly to the author of a shared link is going to be really handy.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/highlighting-journalism-with-the-fediverse-creator-tag/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:56:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>似乎 Perplexity 还不够糟糕，他们还热链接图片</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/as-if-perplexity-didnt-suck-enough-theyre-also-hotlinking-images/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Perplexity, robots.txt, prompt injection, hotlinking, nginx

要点1: Perplexity忽视了robots.txt规则，不仅爬取网站内容，还在他们的服务器上请求图像，浪费带宽，并造成额外成本。
要点2: Perplexity的做法让作者感到愤怒，认为他们不尊重规则，还在盗用别人的带宽。
要点3: 作者提供了Nginx的解决方案，在请求Perplexity AI的图像时重定向到特定图片，表达愤怒情绪。
要点4: 作者并不直接在自己的域上托管许多图片，因此Nginx的解决方案对他并不适用，但Bunny可能有一种能解决这个问题的方法。
要点5: 总结：作者对Perplexity的行为感到愤怒，并表达了对其的不满。希望他们能尊重他人的劳动成果和资源，并不要再侵犯他人的利益。 
Ben has an excellent post expanding on my findings about Perplexity ignoring robots.txt. He also digs into the various ways prompt injection does and doesn&#39;t work. The entire post is well worth your time but this part really jumped out at me:

When I searched about creating an end for our sofa, Perplexity hotlinked some photos from that post which resulting in my browser requesting them from my server.
They&#39;re wasting my bandwidth to serve content to their users. For many sites, there&#39;s a tangible cost associated with every byte served - they are literally costing me money (albeit a small amount)

So not only can&#39;t they be trusted to follow the de facto rules about scraping websites, they&#39;re also hotlinking? Can they not spare any of the millions of dollars they&#39;ve raised to actually cache the images they&#39;re serving up. &quot;Might as well just use someone else&#39;s bandwidth&quot;. Dickheads.
Ben offers a solution to this for nginx, replacing any request for an image from them with an image stating &quot;perplexity just tried to steal my image and my bandwidth&quot;:
location ~*  \.(jpg|jpeg|png|gif|ico|bmp)$ {    # Redirect image fetches from Perplexity AI    if ($http_referer = &quot;https://www.perplexity.ai/&quot;){        rewrite (.*) path/to/image/perplexity_ai.jpg redirect;    }}
I don&#39;t host many images directly on this domain but rather put them on Bunny CDN so nginx won&#39;t help me here. Thankfully, Bunny has a way to block specific referrers. I don&#39;t get to do a funny image but this is close enough.

I know I said my last post would be my final word but this really pissed me off. So once again, fuck you Perplexity.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/as-if-perplexity-didnt-suck-enough-theyre-also-hotlinking-images/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 11:31:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perplexity AI、Robots.txt 及其他问题</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/perplexity-ai-robotstxt-and-other-questions/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/perplexity-ai-robotstxt-and-other-questions/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 11:12:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>向 Eleventy 添加 Github 风格的 Markdown 提醒</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/adding-githubstyle-markdown-alerts-to-eleventy/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 更新模块、Markdown、Eleventy、CSS、插件
更新模块和插件让作者的博客更新更有条理，Markdown语法简单易用，配合Eleventy使用更方便；CSS样式调整使插件输出的更新模块颜色搭配网站风格统一。总结: 更新模块插件让作者博客更新更有条理，使用Markdown和Eleventy更便捷，CSS调整让模块颜色与网站风格更加统一。 
I often have occasion to come back to a blog post and add some kind of update. Maybe I changed my mind or someone offered some new information I hadn&#39;t seen at the time of writing. Up until now I would just add updates willy-nilly; sometimes they&#39;d be at the start, sometimes the end, sometimes in bold, sometimes not. What I wanted was something standard I could use and ideally with Markdown.
GitHub has alerts (aka callouts) Markdown support where the syntax looks like this:
&gt; [!NOTE]  &gt; Highlights information that users should take into account, even when skimming.&gt; [!TIP]&gt; Optional information to help a user be more successful.&gt; [!IMPORTANT]  &gt; Crucial information necessary for users to succeed.&gt; [!WARNING]  &gt; Critical content demanding immediate user attention due to potential risks.&gt; [!CAUTION]&gt; Negative potential consequences of an action.
These different types have different colors and icons on GitHub. I figured these would be perfect for my update blocks if I could just do:
&gt; [!NOTE] Update 2024-06-20&gt; This is the update that has happened
Thankfully someone had made a plugin to handle this with markdown-it, the renderer I use for this site: markdown-it-github-alerts. I installed the package and added it to my Eleventy config:
let markdownLib =  markdownIt(options)	.use(require(&quot;markdown-it-footnote&quot;))+	.use(require(&#39;markdown-it-github-alerts&#39;))
I also pulled in the CSS from the package into my CSS config and made a few tweaks: I&#39;ve no intention of using anything other than the NOTE type so I wanted the colors to match my site rather than use GitHub&#39;s colors.

Finally I went and updated a bunch of old posts that had updates.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/adding-githubstyle-markdown-alerts-to-eleventy/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 11:26:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perplexity AI 在用户代理方面撒谎</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/perplexity-ai-is-lying-about-its-user-agent/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/perplexity-ai-is-lying-about-its-user-agent/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 14:16:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>使用 Nginx 阻止机器人</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/blocking-bots-with-nginx/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/blocking-bots-with-nginx/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 07:26:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>这是我的/下一个</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/this-is-my-next/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ /where /someday movie TV show watch API
管理/watchlist页面内容及API联动，实时更新想看的电影电视剧和游戏，也包含了项目笔记。/next页面展示了KnightCMS的API端点数据，被Eleventy读取并展示出来。解决了忘记推荐影视作品的问题，提供了一个方便的参考清单。总结: 该文章介绍了作者新增了/where和/someday页面，区分了两者的功能。其中/someday页面用于记录未来的期望和目标，而/next页面用于记录想要观看的电影、电视剧以及玩的游戏等娱乐内容。作者通过KnightCMS和Eleventy的API联动实现了数据管理和展示，解决了忘记观看内容的问题。 
This week I added /where and /someday to the Slashpages site. I started making my own someday page, which is still in progress, but it got me thinking about a similar but distinct page: /next.
I see this page as a toned-down version of someday: rather than my hopes, dreams, and goals, it&#39;s movies and TV shows I want to watch, games I want to play, projects I want to start, that kind of thing.
With the work I&#39;ve done on KnightCMS, I&#39;m able to manage the content on this page easily from anywhere. Add a new show I want to watch, remove a book I&#39;ve started (and add it to my /now page), as well as add some notes about projects. This data is exposed on an API endpoint in KnightCMS which is then pulled into an Eleventy data file to display on the page. Here&#39;s what the /next list looks like in the CMS:

I have a real problem with forgetting which movies and TV shows I thought looked interesting so this page will serve as a reference when I&#39;m looking for something to watch.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/this-is-my-next/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 14:25:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WeblogPoMo 回顾</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/weblogpomo-retrospective/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/weblogpomo-retrospective/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:48:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>