<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Robb Knight • 帖子 • Atom Feed</title>
    <link>https://rknight.me/subscribe/posts/atom.xml</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 12:28:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>似乎 Perplexity 还不够糟糕，他们还热链接图片</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/as-if-perplexity-didnt-suck-enough-theyre-also-hotlinking-images/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ Perplexity, robots.txt, prompt injection, hotlinking, nginx

要点1: Perplexity忽视了robots.txt规则，不仅爬取网站内容，还在他们的服务器上请求图像，浪费带宽，并造成额外成本。
要点2: Perplexity的做法让作者感到愤怒，认为他们不尊重规则，还在盗用别人的带宽。
要点3: 作者提供了Nginx的解决方案，在请求Perplexity AI的图像时重定向到特定图片，表达愤怒情绪。
要点4: 作者并不直接在自己的域上托管许多图片，因此Nginx的解决方案对他并不适用，但Bunny可能有一种能解决这个问题的方法。
要点5: 总结：作者对Perplexity的行为感到愤怒，并表达了对其的不满。希望他们能尊重他人的劳动成果和资源，并不要再侵犯他人的利益。 
Ben has an excellent post expanding on my findings about Perplexity ignoring robots.txt. He also digs into the various ways prompt injection does and doesn&#39;t work. The entire post is well worth your time but this part really jumped out at me:

When I searched about creating an end for our sofa, Perplexity hotlinked some photos from that post which resulting in my browser requesting them from my server.
They&#39;re wasting my bandwidth to serve content to their users. For many sites, there&#39;s a tangible cost associated with every byte served - they are literally costing me money (albeit a small amount)

So not only can&#39;t they be trusted to follow the de facto rules about scraping websites, they&#39;re also hotlinking? Can they not spare any of the millions of dollars they&#39;ve raised to actually cache the images they&#39;re serving up. &quot;Might as well just use someone else&#39;s bandwidth&quot;. Dickheads.
Ben offers a solution to this for nginx, replacing any request for an image from them with an image stating &quot;perplexity just tried to steal my image and my bandwidth&quot;:
location ~*  \.(jpg|jpeg|png|gif|ico|bmp)$ {    # Redirect image fetches from Perplexity AI    if ($http_referer = &quot;https://www.perplexity.ai/&quot;){        rewrite (.*) path/to/image/perplexity_ai.jpg redirect;    }}
I don&#39;t host many images directly on this domain but rather put them on Bunny CDN so nginx won&#39;t help me here. Thankfully, Bunny has a way to block specific referrers. I don&#39;t get to do a funny image but this is close enough.

I know I said my last post would be my final word but this really pissed me off. So once again, fuck you Perplexity.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/as-if-perplexity-didnt-suck-enough-theyre-also-hotlinking-images/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 11:31:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perplexity AI、Robots.txt 及其他问题</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/perplexity-ai-robotstxt-and-other-questions/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/perplexity-ai-robotstxt-and-other-questions/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 11:12:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>向 Eleventy 添加 Github 风格的 Markdown 提醒</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/adding-githubstyle-markdown-alerts-to-eleventy/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 更新模块、Markdown、Eleventy、CSS、插件
更新模块和插件让作者的博客更新更有条理，Markdown语法简单易用，配合Eleventy使用更方便；CSS样式调整使插件输出的更新模块颜色搭配网站风格统一。总结: 更新模块插件让作者博客更新更有条理，使用Markdown和Eleventy更便捷，CSS调整让模块颜色与网站风格更加统一。 
I often have occasion to come back to a blog post and add some kind of update. Maybe I changed my mind or someone offered some new information I hadn&#39;t seen at the time of writing. Up until now I would just add updates willy-nilly; sometimes they&#39;d be at the start, sometimes the end, sometimes in bold, sometimes not. What I wanted was something standard I could use and ideally with Markdown.
GitHub has alerts (aka callouts) Markdown support where the syntax looks like this:
&gt; [!NOTE]  &gt; Highlights information that users should take into account, even when skimming.&gt; [!TIP]&gt; Optional information to help a user be more successful.&gt; [!IMPORTANT]  &gt; Crucial information necessary for users to succeed.&gt; [!WARNING]  &gt; Critical content demanding immediate user attention due to potential risks.&gt; [!CAUTION]&gt; Negative potential consequences of an action.
These different types have different colors and icons on GitHub. I figured these would be perfect for my update blocks if I could just do:
&gt; [!NOTE] Update 2024-06-20&gt; This is the update that has happened
Thankfully someone had made a plugin to handle this with markdown-it, the renderer I use for this site: markdown-it-github-alerts. I installed the package and added it to my Eleventy config:
let markdownLib =  markdownIt(options)	.use(require(&quot;markdown-it-footnote&quot;))+	.use(require(&#39;markdown-it-github-alerts&#39;))
I also pulled in the CSS from the package into my CSS config and made a few tweaks: I&#39;ve no intention of using anything other than the NOTE type so I wanted the colors to match my site rather than use GitHub&#39;s colors.

Finally I went and updated a bunch of old posts that had updates.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/adding-githubstyle-markdown-alerts-to-eleventy/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 11:26:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perplexity AI 在用户代理方面撒谎</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/perplexity-ai-is-lying-about-its-user-agent/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/perplexity-ai-is-lying-about-its-user-agent/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 14:16:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>使用 Nginx 阻止机器人</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/blocking-bots-with-nginx/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/blocking-bots-with-nginx/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 07:26:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>这是我的/下一个</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/this-is-my-next/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ /where /someday movie TV show watch API
管理/watchlist页面内容及API联动，实时更新想看的电影电视剧和游戏，也包含了项目笔记。/next页面展示了KnightCMS的API端点数据，被Eleventy读取并展示出来。解决了忘记推荐影视作品的问题，提供了一个方便的参考清单。总结: 该文章介绍了作者新增了/where和/someday页面，区分了两者的功能。其中/someday页面用于记录未来的期望和目标，而/next页面用于记录想要观看的电影、电视剧以及玩的游戏等娱乐内容。作者通过KnightCMS和Eleventy的API联动实现了数据管理和展示，解决了忘记观看内容的问题。 
This week I added /where and /someday to the Slashpages site. I started making my own someday page, which is still in progress, but it got me thinking about a similar but distinct page: /next.
I see this page as a toned-down version of someday: rather than my hopes, dreams, and goals, it&#39;s movies and TV shows I want to watch, games I want to play, projects I want to start, that kind of thing.
With the work I&#39;ve done on KnightCMS, I&#39;m able to manage the content on this page easily from anywhere. Add a new show I want to watch, remove a book I&#39;ve started (and add it to my /now page), as well as add some notes about projects. This data is exposed on an API endpoint in KnightCMS which is then pulled into an Eleventy data file to display on the page. Here&#39;s what the /next list looks like in the CMS:

I have a real problem with forgetting which movies and TV shows I thought looked interesting so this page will serve as a reference when I&#39;m looking for something to watch.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/this-is-my-next/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 14:25:34 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WeblogPoMo 回顾</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/weblogpomo-retrospective/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/weblogpomo-retrospective/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:48:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>相反的实验：报告一</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/the-converse-experiment-report-one/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 婚礼、Converse、耐用性、鞋子磨损、记录
总结:文章介绍了作者在婚礼上穿着Converse Chuck Taylor All Star的经历，首次穿着后每日穿着，通过记录发现耐用性。在婚礼后196天，鞋底开始与鞋面脱离，于254天后发现鞋垫开始磨损。作者通过细致的记录，为未来衡量Converse鞋子的耐用性提供了有用参考。 
When I got married, I wore a suit and a pair of black Converse Chuck Taylor All Star&#39;s. They were brand new and the first time I wore them was the day of our wedding.
The day after I just put them on because the wedding was over and they could just go into the normal shoe rotation. Then a month went by and I realised I had worn them every day which gave me a data point I wish I&#39;d done for the many other pairs of Converse I&#39;ve bought over the years: how long does a pair actually last? I had a vague idea but nothing concrete.
All was well until the 23rd of March, 196 days after the wedding, and the outer sole started to come apart from the upper. A pretty standard place for All Stars to start to fail.
Then this month on the 20th, 254 days after, I noticed the insoles are starting to wear a bit thin which is fine for now, but I may need to retire them soon.
Yes, I took notes on when things started to break because I&#39;ve never had the opportunity to measure this before. I will report back when they are no more.]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/the-converse-experiment-report-one/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 14:20:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>链接转储#4</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/link-dump-4/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ famicon, design competition, 8BitDo, Super ABXY, handheld game consoles

设计比赛中，人们设计了假冒的 famicon 游戏封面，这是一个光荣的活动。8BitDo 推出了一些新的游戏手柄，我肯定会购买 Super ABXY。文章中列出了各种可用的掌上游戏机。 

总结:设计比赛中人们设计了伪造的 famicon 游戏封面，8BitDo 推出了新产品 Super ABXY，同时也对各种掌上游戏机做了介绍。 
My Famicase Exhibition 2024 - A design competition where people design fake famicon game covers.
This 3D printed mechanical digital clock is glorious.
Look Mum, No Breakpoints! - A great intro into using CSS clamp for fluid design.
8BitDo have some new keyboard extensions. I&#39;ll definitely be buying the Super ABXY.
Handheld List. Excellent list of the various handheld game consoles that are available.
No Web Without Women
Manifesto for a Humane Web
RPG-Awesome | A fantasy themed font and CSS toolkit]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/link-dump-4/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 18:40:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>添加年鉴封面</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/adding-covers-to-almanac/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/adding-covers-to-almanac/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 08:18:19 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>大麦肉酱食谱</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/orzo-bolognese-recipe/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[ 我们为 Baby Knight 使用的简单食谱 
Baby Knight 吃不够的非常简单的食谱。
配料：

500 克牛肉碎
500 克番茄酱
250 克意大利面
1 块牛肉汤块
磨碎的奶酪


在平底锅中将碎肉煎黄
加入番茄酱、汤块和意大利面，再加入 250 毫升水
小火煮约 20 分钟，偶尔搅拌，否则会粘在一起
加入奶酪和任何你喜欢的调味料

非常简单。这可以冷冻相当多的份量。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/orzo-bolognese-recipe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 08:06:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>从档案中保存的两篇游戏帖子</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/two-game-posts-saved-from-the-archives/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[在年鉴上工作以确保所有帖子都包含所需的所有信息和图像时，我发现两篇不太适合的帖子。这两个都是基于 2018 年在 Twitter 上流传的 meme，所以我把它们移到了这里，以便于大家可以轻松找到。
#GameStruck4
这个是在 Twitter 上流传的，我想是来自这篇 Vice 帖子。

你的 #GameStruck4 是什么，定义你的四款游戏？



Mario Kart 64
杰克与达斯特
托尼·霍克职业滑板 3
侠盗猎车手：罪恶都市

其他竞争者：

神奇宝贝红色/蓝色
塞尔达传说：时之笛
黄金眼 64
荒野大镖客
神秘海域 4：盗贼末路
地平线零Dawn
Life Is Strange

通过视频游戏了解我
根据帖子的注释，我在这里看到了这个模因。
最喜欢的女性视频游戏角色：Aloy，地平线零之曙光
一款非常糟糕但又非常好的游戏：Bishi Bashi Special，PS1
一款触动你内心情感的游戏：Gone Home
最喜欢的游戏开发商或工作室：顽皮狗
最喜欢的电子游戏男角色：萨利机长、神秘海域
一款很少有人谈论的游戏：暗影记忆、PS2
最喜欢的反派（小心剧透）：菲兹科、日落超速
小时候最喜欢的游戏：托尼霍克职业滑板 3
一款你从未感兴趣的游戏或系列：任天堂明星大乱斗
一款永远不会过时的游戏：马里奥赛车
一款每个人都应该至少玩一次的游戏：荒野大镖客救赎
最喜欢的游戏类型：单人故事驱动
你现在真的应该玩的游戏：最后生还者
你最近玩过的最喜欢的独立游戏：高尔夫故事]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/two-game-posts-saved-from-the-archives/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 11:40:05 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>使用 Karabiner Elements 修复 8BitDo 键盘上的双音量跳跃问题</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/fix-double-volume-jump-on-8bitdo-keyboard-with-karabiner-elements/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/fix-double-volume-jump-on-8bitdo-keyboard-with-karabiner-elements/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 13:10:57 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>射线投射跟进</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/raycast-follow-up/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[继我关于 Raycast 的两篇帖子之后，我收到了一些关于我遗漏的一些内容的反馈。
Dean 指出，我用于打开常用文件夹的脚本是不必要的，因为 Raycast 有一个 Quicklinks 扩展，可用于打开文件、文件夹和网站。

他还提到了 Raycast 的另一个我没有意识到的功能：搜索屏幕截图扩展。这会搜索您的屏幕截图文件夹，以便您可以将其中一个复制到剪贴板并提取文本。

最后Dave 向我指出 音板扩展，我可以将其用于我的 Brian Butterfield 音板。]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/raycast-follow-up/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 07:31:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>尝试 Raycast：第二部分</title>
      <link>https://rknight.me/blog/trying-raycast-part-two/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <guid>https://rknight.me/blog/trying-raycast-part-two/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 07:26:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>